-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译: Grim ch1plus1
校对: Grim
时间轴调整: 程风吹雪
我总相信 是那些你没法选择的事物
I always believed it was the things you don't choose
造就了你
that makes you who you are.
你的家乡
Your city.
你的邻里
Your neighborhood.
你的亲人
Your family.
这里的人总是为这些事物骄傲
People here take pride in these things.
好像那是他们的成就
Like it was something they'd accomplished.
他们的灵魂包裹在皮囊里
The bodies around their souls.
然后又被城市笼罩
The cities wrapped around those.
片名: 《失踪的宝贝》
我这辈子一直住在这个街区
I lived on this block my whole life.
这些人多数也一样
Most of these people have.
既然我的工作是寻找失踪者
When your job is to find people who are missing,
知道他们的老家在哪里总是有帮助的
it helps to know where they started.
我找的是那些
I find the people who started in the cracks,
钻进地缝里不见的人
and then fell through.
这座城市或许很残酷
This city can be hard.
小时候我问牧师 怎样才能既保证自己上天堂
When I was young, I asked my priest how you could get to heaven
又不被世上的各种邪恶力量吞噬
and still protect yourself from all the evil in the world.
他告诉我 上帝是这么对自己的孩子说的
He told me what God said to his children.
"你们是狼群中的羔羊"
"You are sheep among wolves,
"既要像毒蛇一样精明"
"be wise as serpents,
"也要像鸽子一样清白"
"yet innocent as doves."
太太 你就住在马路对面 是吗?
You live just across the street. Is that right, ma'am?
拐角上那座就是我的房子
That one on the corner, that's our house.
你知道 让安妮特上高中 要…
You know, to get Annette in high school, you have...
- 我听说他们办了开幕式 - 对 我也听说了
- I heard they had an opening. - Yeah, me, too.
关键是 她脸上总是挂着微笑
The thing is, she always had a smile on her face.
她就是这样 一直在笑
That was her. She was always smiling.
谁会拐走我的小姑娘?
I mean, who would take my little girl?
她从没伤害过任何人 从没…
She never hurt anybody, never caused...
不管你是谁 如果她在你手上
Whoever you are, if you have her,
马上放了她
you just let her go.
我们不会起诉你
Now, we won't charge you,
如果你听到我说话 快让她回家
but if you're out there, just let her come home.
好吗?让她回家
All right? Let her come home.
谁会拐走我的小姑娘?
I mean, who would take my little girl?
- 他妈的警察 - 她从没闯过祸
- You fucking cops. - She never caused no trouble,
她从没打过架 她是个小乖乖
she never got in any fights, she's a sweetheart.
- 这也太夸张了 - 她是个好孩子
- This is just unbelievable. - She was a good kid.
警察全体出动 站在那房子外面
The whole force standing outside the house,
背着手 守在人行道上
guarding the sidewalk with their arms crossed.
我是说 难道绑匪又回来了?
I mean, are the kidnappers coming back?
阿曼达·麦克雷蒂被人从家中绑走
Amanda McCready was taken from her home
时间是星期三晚上8:00到8:30之间
between 8:00 and 8:30 Wednesday night.
她今年四岁 金发 绿眼…
She's four years old, has blond hair and green eyes...
…体重35磅 身高40英寸
- Hey. - Hey.
...weighs 35 pounds and is 40 inches tall.
- 你知道我爱你 对吗? - 对 我知道
- You know I love you, right? - Yeah. I know.
饱受指责的警察和疲惫不堪的市民
A beleaguered police force and a weary citizenry
只能指望少得可怜的一点线索
have been left with so little to cling to.
一条毯子 一个后门 和一个名叫米拉贝尔的布娃娃
A blanket, a back door, and a doll named Mirabelle.
街坊邻居都集合起来了
The neighborhood's really coming together.
我们要开个会
We're gonna have a rally.
每个人都要警戒 今晚我们要守夜
Everyone's gonna have a vigil. We're gonna have a vigil tonight.
邻居们都提高了警惕
You know, the neighborhood's all alert,
每个人都在注意有什么风吹草动…
everybody's alert of what's going on and everything that...
我们在周围发了传单 贴了寻人启事 我们全都做了
The surroundings. We got flyers up, posters up, we have all that stuff up.
让大家都知道这事 让大家都来找阿曼达
So everybody's well aware and everybody's looking for Amanda.
在相关新闻里 负责预防针对儿童犯罪的
In related news, the Boston police captain
波士顿警监
responsible for preventing crimes against children
刚刚说了一些
spoke a few words a moment ago,
安慰的话语
words of comfort.
我理解失去女儿的痛苦 我们不会辜负大家
I know the pain of losing a daughter. We will not fail.
我们将追查每一条线索
We will pursue every avenue.
你了解那个妈妈吗?
Do you know the mother?
杰克·道伊尔警监详细介绍失踪的 多尔切斯特女孩…
Captain Jack Doyle on details of the missing Dorchester girl...
稍微知道一点 那时我是新生 她是高年级的
Little bit. I was a freshman, she was a senior.
她在柱子下面给麦克·古雷口交
She was blowing Mike Gulley down the post
那时他还是14岁的纯真少男 在佛蒙特州给奶牛挤奶
when he was still 14 and innocent and milking cows up Vermont.
我不知道什么叫纯真
I don't know about innocent.
据母亲说 阿曼达可能带着自己的一个娃娃
Her mother says Amanda may be carrying a little girl of her own.
人们最后一次看到阿曼达时 她和她最喜欢的娃娃米拉贝尔在一起
Mirabelle was last seen with Amanda. It's her favorite doll.
这太可怕了
This is horrible.
- 如果你是电视台 就不会这么想了 - 关了它
- Not if you're Channel 9. - Turn it off.
晚安
Good night.
- 喂 安姬 去开门吧? - 我在浴室里
- Hey, Angie. Get the door? - I'm in the bathroom.
他妈的才7:00!大清早的!
It's 7:00! Seven in the fucking morning!
怎么?
What?
你是帕特里克·肯奇吗?
Are you Patrick Kenzie?
- 是 - 碧·麦克雷蒂和莱昂内尔·麦克雷蒂
- Yeah. - Bea and Lionel McCready.
我们的外甥女三天前被绑架了
Our niece was kidnapped three days ago.
请进 请进 真对不起
Please, come on in. Come on in. I have to apologize.
邻居家的孩子爱捣蛋
You know, there's been some problems with kids in the neighborhood,
他们老是按了门铃就跑
kind of ding-dong ditch, ringing the buzzer and running away.
所以我刚才会爆粗口
So that's the reason for the language.
- 哦 - 我们可以晚点再来
- Oh. - Well, we can come back later.
不用 不用 别客气
No. Please, please. Make yourself comfortable.
来吧 我们就是… 对不起 这里太乱了
Here, we're just... I'm sorry about the mess.
我们一直在… 我最近有个案子 还有很多其他案子
We've been... I had a late case, and a lot of cases.
我们一直在… 一直在工作
We've just been... We've just been working a lot,
昨晚还在弄一个案子 所以我们…
we worked on a case last night, you know, so we just...
总之 请坐吧
Please sit down, though.
或者…
Or...
我的合伙人马上就过来 她在别的房间里
My associate'll be in in just a minute. She's in the other room.
有什么要我们帮忙的?
How can we help you?
你知道在街坊邻居里
Do you know people in the neighborhood
有人不肯和警察说话吧?
who don't talk to the police?
对 有一两个
Yeah, one or two.
我们想雇你们来加强对阿曼达的调查
We wanna hire you to augment the investigation of Amanda.
是吗?
Is that right?
你知道在拉姆西案*里 那家人雇了 私家侦探吧? （*1996年轰动全美的儿童选美皇后被害案 案犯在2006年才落网）
You know how in JonBenet Ramsey the family hired investigators?
那么… 你们雇外人帮忙 警察没意见吗?
So... Are the police all right with youse hiring outside help?
警察应该关心的是怎么找到我的外甥女
The police need to worry about finding my niece.
嗨 我是安姬·杰纳罗 是帕特里克的同事
Hi. I'm Angie Gennaro. I work with Patrick.
你好 我是碧·麦克雷蒂 这是我丈夫莱昂内尔
Hello. I'm Bea McCready. This is my husband, Lionel.
- 你好 - 他们想雇我们
- How do you do? - They wanna hire us
来加强调查
to augment the investigation.
你们该去找精密侦探事务所
You should talk to Precision Investigators.
- 谁?我… - 我不知道 我的意思是…
- Who? I... - I don't know, I meant...
我们听他们说吧 安姬
Well, let's hear them out, Ange.
你们不是专找失踪者的侦探吗?
Well, aren't you missing persons detectives?
对 你们在报上登的广告就是这么写的
Yeah, that's what your ad says in the paper.
没错 我们是专找失踪者的侦探
Yeah, we are. We are missing persons detectives.
对不起 她… 我想安姬的意思是说
I'm sorry, she... I think that what Angie means to say is,
是这么回事 应该向你们说明
just for the sake of disclosure, up to this point,
我们的经验主要在于 寻找那些失踪者
our experience has been primarily, you know, finding missing persons
那些家伙失踪是因为…
who've gone missing that they...
他们不肯再交动力雪橇的分期付款
You know, they just stop payments on their Jet Ski
搬到新罕布什尔州去了…
and they went to New Hampshire...
现在本州的每个警察都在找你们的外甥女
Every police officer in this state is looking for your niece right now.
我不敢说我们能帮多少忙
And I'm not sure how much more help we could be.
你们来帮忙也没有坏处 对吗?
Well, you're not gonna do any harm, are you?
好吧 听我说 我有爱迪生公司给我的养老金
All right, look. I got a pension coming up with Edison.
- 可以用它作抵押 如果… - 不 不是这个意思
- So, that's collateral, if... - No. It's not that.
为什么这么难办? 警察不希望我来这
Why is this so hard? The cops don't want me coming here.
- 莱昂内尔不希望我来这 - 别担心
- Lionel don't want me coming here. - Don't worry.
- 现在你们还不想接这份工作? - 不 我们不是不想接这份工作…
- Now you don't want the job? - No, it's not that we don't want the job...
我们作这样的决定之前 都要先私下商量商量
We consult privately before we make decisions like these.
- 是的 - 那天海琳送她上了床
- We do. - Helene puts her to bed.
然后去道蒂家看电视 大概看了半个钟头
She goes across to Dottie's. Maybe gone a half hour, watches TV.
等她回到家里 阿曼达就不见了
Then she comes home and Amanda is gone.
她看的是《换妻》
She was watching Wife Swap.
她记得很清楚 因为这是她最喜欢的节目
She remembers, 'cause that's her favorite show.
你们俩住在楼上?
And do youse two live upstairs?
对 我们父母去世时给我们 留了一个单元 给我妹妹也留了一个
Yeah, when our folks died they left us a unit and my sister a unit,
所以 你知道 我们基本上别无选择
so, you know, basically we got no choice.
房子里的那些声音
And with the acoustics in the apartment,
也是你躲不过的
you can't get away from it.
你们为什么不过去看看呢?
Why don't you just come over the house, all right?
- 和海琳谈谈吧 - 莱昂内尔 和海琳谈?
- Just talk to Helene, you know. - Lionel, talk to Helene?
她只是没有表现出来 其实她现在很痛苦
Look, she don't show it, but she's hurting right now.
- 拜托 拜托! - 好了 听我说 好吗?
- Please. Please! - All right. Lookit, all right?
我也不是圣人 明白吗? 我也有过自己的问题
I was no saint. All right? I had my own problems.
我在22岁时曾经自暴自弃 是碧让我浪子回头的
I took a hard bust at 22. Bea straightened me out.
我妹妹海琳还没这样的经历
My sister Helene has not had that.
和母亲谈谈是我们起码该做的
Talking to the mother's the least we could do.
- 我们会过去的 - 太谢谢了
- We'll come right over. - Thanks a lot.
不用谢 莱昂内尔
Yeah. Pleasure, Lionel.
我们就住在公园边上那座褐色的 三层公寓楼里
Oh, you'll find us in that brown three-decker by the park.
- 你们知道地址 - 如今那地方你很难迷路了
- You know where it is. - Be hard to miss today.
瞧瞧 天哪
Look at this. Jesus.
全街区的人都聚在这儿了
Fucking block party here.
去年这里有四个佛得角移民被杀
Four Cape Verdeans got killed here last year.
根本没人关心
No one gave a shit.
我们的生活很美好 对吧?
We have a good life, right?
这个问题里有陷阱吧?
Is that a trick question?
我不希望在垃圾箱里找到他们的小孩
I don't wanna find their little kid in a dumpster.
也许她不在垃圾箱里 宝贝
Maybe she's not in a dumpster, babe.
我不希望小孩被虐待三天后才被人找到
I don't wanna find a little kid after they've been abused for three days.
宝贝 没人愿意这样
Hon, nobody does.
好吧
All right.
听我说 我们这就上去和他们谈
Listen, we'll just go up and we'll talk to them,
要是谈过以后你不想接手 我不会和你争的
and you don't wanna do it after that, I won't argue with you.
好的
Okay.
嗨 请进
Hi. Please, come on in.
海琳
Helene.
这是帕特里克·肯奇 安吉拉·杰纳罗
This is Patrick Kenzie, Angela Gennaro.
- 嗨 - 我记得在高中里见过你
- Hi. - I remember you from high school.
我看你还是有点臭架子 嗯?
I see you're still a little conceited, huh?
道蒂 劳驾 回避一下好么?
Would you excuse us, Dottie?
道蒂是我最好的朋友 莱昂内尔 只要她乐意 就可以呆在我家
Dottie's my best friend, Lionel. She could be in my house if she wants.
海琳 我们不想惹你生气
Helene, we don't wanna get in your hair.
我们只想问几个关于你女儿的问题
We're just gonna ask you a couple questions
问完了我们就走
about your daughter, then we'll be out of here.
- 现在人人都想掺一脚了 - 我知道
- Everyone wants their part now. - I know.
我已经跟警察说了四十遍
I already talked to the cops forty times.
- 抱歉 我们又要耽误你的时间 - 我们不是警察
- We're sorry to take up your time. - Listen, we're not the cops.
是碧特丽斯请我们来的
Beatrice asked us to come over here
看看是不是能帮忙找你女儿
and see if we could help out finding your daughter.
碧来管什么闲事? 那是我的孩子
Why don't Bea mind her business? It's my kid.
因为现在人人都想来出风头
'Cause everyone gotta have their moment, now.
- 对吗? - 对
- Right? - Right.
碧特丽斯自己掏钱请这些人 帮忙找阿曼达
Beatrice hired these people to help find Amanda with her own money,
所以说你最好懂点礼貌
so you had better show them the goddamn courtesy
- 对他们放尊重点! - 她现在正伤心呢 混蛋
- and respect they deserve! - She's in grieving, prick.
她想怎么伤心是她的事 道蒂
She could grieve how she wants, Dottie.
- 你又不是这家的人! - 混蛋
- You don't live here! - Asshole.
你他妈的别冲她嚷嚷 莱昂内尔 你又不是她爸爸!
Don't you fucking yell at her, Lionel. You ain't her father!
滚你的 莱昂内尔
Fuck you, Lionel.
回家自慰去吧 操你
Go fuck yourself. Cocksucker. Fuck you.
你给我滚蛋
Get the fuck outta here.
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 对不起 - 也许我们该走了
- I'm sorry. - Maybe we should go.
- 我能理解 对不起 - 没什么
- I understand. I'm sorry. - It's all right.
也许我们该走了?
Maybe we should go?
我们在走廊里说会儿话 好吗?
Look. Can we all just have a few words in the hallway, please?
失陪了 海琳
Excuse us, Helene.
- 海琳的情绪有点问题 - 不是这样的 莱昂内尔
- Helene's got emotional problems. - It's not that, Lionel.
- 那是怎样? - 她是个贱货!
- What is it, then? - She's a cunt!
- 碧特丽斯 别说这种话 - 上帝作证 这是实话
- Beatrice, don't use that word. - God help me, it's true.
这是个孩子 我不知道她在哪儿
This is a child. And I don't know where she is.
唔…
Well...
我们来帮忙也没坏处 对吧?
We can't do any harm, right?
好了 碧 好了
It's all right, Bea. It's all right, Bea. Huh?
谢谢
Thank you.
那么…
Now...
她很文静 一直在努力做个好孩子
Well, she's quiet. She tries very hard to be a good girl.
说说海琳吧?她的朋友怎样? 和她来往的人呢?
What about Helene? Her friends? People she hangs out with?
有很多人来她家作客吗?
She got a lot of people come by the house?
我不知道 她总是泡在菲尔莫
I don't know. She's at the Fillmore all the time.
在菲尔莫酒馆?
She's at the Fillmore Lounge?
对 她天天喝酒
Yeah, she drinks every day.
她这是遗传的 胎里毛病 我们的父母也是这样
She's got the gene, you know? The disease. Our parents had it, too.
她嗑药吗?
She use drugs?
我想她会吸一点可卡因
I think she does a little coke.
一点是多少?
How much is a little?
我不知道 大概一星期有几次吧 怎样才算是很多?
I don't know. Few times a week, maybe. I mean, how much is a lot?
一星期几次已经很多了
Few times a week's a lot.
那么她吸得很多 这种事我不清楚的
Then she does a lot. I don't know anything about that.
我是自己戒掉的 已经23年没碰过了 所以我身体很好
I put the plug in the jug myself, I got 23 years sobriety, so, I'm good.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
让我看看她的房间你们不介意吧?
Do you mind if we see her room?
- 连家具也绑走了? - 帕特里克
- Kidnapped the furniture, too? - Patrick.
下班人员调查
10-7 investigation.
还没解决?
Solved it yet?
警监 我是帕特里克·肯奇 这是我的合伙人安姬·杰纳罗
Captain, Patrick Kenzie. This is my associate, Angie Gennaro.
嗯哼?
Mmm-hmm?
我看见碧特丽斯出去雇了些人
I see Beatrice went on and hired someone.
我想这应该不是你的建议
I take it that wasn't your recommendation.
不是
It was not.
那女人为了雇每一个肯收信用卡的 家伙 会把房子全抵押出去
That woman would mortgage her home to every snake doctor
只要她觉得他们能帮忙找她外甥女
taking credit cards if she thought it would help find her niece.
我的工作已经够难了 还要应付这些耍把戏的
My job's hard enough without inviting the circus in here.
警监 我们做这事不是为了钱
Captain, this isn't about the money for us.
你们以前调查过诱拐案吗?
You ever investigated an abduction before?
我想麦克雷蒂太太是希望我们
I think Mrs. McCready was hoping we could help
看在街坊邻居的份上出一把力 警民协作嘛
with the neighborhood aspect of this investigation, the people, you know.
你多大了?
How old are you?
- 我31了 - 他是娃娃脸
- I'm 31. - He just looks young.
一个四岁的孩子被拐走了
A four-year-old child is on the street.
已经过了76个小时都不止
It's 76 hours and counting.
找到孩子的前景
And the prospects for where she might be
已经不太乐观了 你明白吗?
are beginning to look grim, you understand?
这种案子里有一半的孩子立刻就被杀了
Half of all the children in these cases are killed, flat out.
要是不能在第一天抓住绑匪
If we don't catch the abductor by day one,
只有大约10%的案子能破
only about 10% are ever solved.
现在是第三天了
This is day three.
他也许是娃娃脸
He may look young,
可要是他想办这个案子 最好别真像娃娃一样
but if he wants to work this case, he'd better not act it.
哦 他是被一起犯罪案件的 受害妇女雇佣了
Well, he's been hired by a woman who's the victim of a crime,
按照法律 他有权代表她
and by law he's entitled as her representative
与波士顿警察局合作
to be cooperated with by the Boston Police Department.
所以他希望得到配合
So he expects to be.
他会得到的
And he will be.
我的两个高级助手会在方便的时候
He and his better half will be contacted by two of my senior men,
和他以及他老婆联系 并允许他们观察
at their convenience, and be permitted to observe.
我们只想帮点忙 警监
We're just trying to help, Captain.
我不在乎是谁干的 只要干成了就行
Look, I don't care who does it. I just want it done.
午安
Good afternoon.
可以开始了吧?
Ready to get started?
我只是说 我们听说海琳常来这儿
All I'm saying is that we heard Helene comes in here.
我们又没问你保险柜的密码
We're not asking for the combination to the safe.
听着 我一个字都不会说的 我已经跟警察说过了
Listen, I ain't saying a fucking word. I already talked to the fucking cops.
好吧
All right.
- 你叫戴夫 对吧? - 大号戴夫
- Dave, right? - Big Dave.
大号戴夫 好的
Big Dave. All right.
我是中号帕特里克 很高兴认识你
I'm Medium Patrick. Nice to meet you.
跟我耍嘴皮子 你是不是觉得屁眼痒了?
You're a little fucking light in the ass to be talking shit, ain't ya?
天哪 朋友 我只是玩玩而已
Jesus, pal, I'm just playing.
听着 你不买酒就滚蛋
Listen, buy a couple of fucking drinks or screw.
我吧 我们要点汽水
Okay, we'll take a couple tonics.
天哪
Jesus Christ.
史蒂夫·彭特罗达吉斯! "希腊方程式"!
Steve Penteroudakis! The Grecian Formula!
哦 操!你们来这里干什么?
Oh, shit! What are you doing here?
你这小流氓在菲尔莫 过得怎样?
Look at this little motherfucker at the Fillmore, what's up?
希腊小子!
Gyro!
啤酒加博彩 下午2:00
Beers and keno, 2:00 in the afternoon.
- 过得怎样? - 还好
- What up? - Oh, yeah.
听我说 我所有地方都去了
Yeah, listen, I been fucking everywhere
贴寻人启事 你们知道吧?
putting up posters, man, you know?
每个小区的走道上 City Point周围 全去了
Every project hallway, all over City Point, everywhere.
你知道吗?这事可真惨
You know? I mean, it's a real tragedy.
她也来过这里 就坐在吧台边
She used to come in here, sit up at the bar and shit.
- 她就像是我的吉祥物 - 海琳带阿曼达来过这里?
- You know, she was like our mascot. - Helene brought Amanda in here?
不 基本上是下午来的 在晚上这可不是孩子呆的地方
No, mostly in the afternoons. I mean, it's no place for a child at night.
- 真的? - 嗯
- Really? - Oh, yeah.
打架的 吸毒的 多了 相信我
Hot tempers, lot of drugs, trust me.
海琳经常来这里吗?
So how often Helene come down here?
每星期有五个晚上在这
Five nights a week.
别不信 哥们 她是个瘾君子 骚货
Come on, guys, please. She's a fucking coke ho, okay?
她差不多每晚都在这里吸粉
She's in here fucking doing lines just about every night.
相信我 好吗? 又不是什么稀奇的事…
Trust me, all right? It's not a real shocker, so...
- 她有这么坏吗? - 唔?
- She's that bad, huh? - Huh?
哦 她坏透了
Oh, she's fucking terrible.
听我说 还记得小孩被绑架的那天晚上吗?
Listen, remember that night when the kid got kidnapped?
你看到她上新闻了 对吧?
You saw her on the news, right?
她说: "哦 我在邻居家里呆了半个钟头"
She's saying, "Oh, I was at my neighbor's house for a half hour."
放屁 她就在这里 吸了大概两个钟头的粉
Bullshit. She was in here for, like, two hours bumping rails. Oh, yeah.
- 她什么时候进来的? - 8:00
- What time did she come in? - 8:00.
- 你确定是那天晚上? - 千真万确
- Are you sure it was the same night? - Fucking positive,
因为她吸了粉以后就在厕所里和雷干
'cause she was in the shitter, fucking banging down rails with Ray,
我在外面砸门
and I was banging on the fucking door.
- 哪个雷?瘦猴雷? - 对 雷·利堪斯基
- Who, Ray? Skinny Ray? - Yeah. Ray Likanski.
他像个基佬一样躲着我
He's in there ducking me like a fucking faggot.
我就去砸门
I was banging on the door.
他以为我不知道他在里面
He thought I didn't know he was in there,
可我知道他准在
but I know he's fucking in there.
- 一分钱都别借给他… - 嘿 史蒂夫
- Don't lend him any money... - Hey, Stevie.
- 你他妈的在干啥? - 没啥 怎么了 列尼?
- What the fuck you doing? - Nothing. What's up, Lenny?
别跟人说你不知道的事
Don't talk about people you don't know.
你这话什么意思? 这些人是我的朋友
What do you mean? These are my friends.
- 我认识他们好多年了 - 有什么问题 伙计?
- I know them for years. - What's the problem, guy?
你说你不是警察 对吗 伙计?
You said you weren't a cop. Right, "guy"?
- 对 我不是警察 - 哦 那你还不快滚?
- Yeah, I'm not a cop. - Yeah, then why don't you fuck off?
关你屁事?
Why don't you mind your business?
他是来这里放屁玩的?
He's gonna come in here and be a smartass?
你还真关心别人的屁啊 戴夫
You're awfully worried about people's asses there, Dave.
哦 没准你的屁眼就像个上好的花瓶
Yeah, you probably got a fucking ass like a Skippy jar.
话说回来 你来这里干啥? 戴夫可调不出像样的马提尼酒
What are you doing here, anyway? Dave can't make a martini worth a shit.
帮海琳找她女儿 不可以么?
Trying to help Helene find her daughter. Is that all right?
听着 别来这儿耍贫嘴
Listen, don't come in here running your mouth,
你以为你比我强?
thinking you're better than me.
你找错了人
I'm not the fucking one.
- 好吧 大家冷静点 - 冷静点
- All right, just cool it. - Cool it.
- 听听这烂人的话 - 这小子操她的时候肯定到一半就痿了
- Listen to this douchebag. - Bet she fucks this asshole in half.
天哪 你们到底什么毛病?
Jesus Christ. What the fuck is the matter with you guys?
你 你个仆街废柴烂货
You, you punk fucking jackass.
我们走 行了吧?
We're leaving, all right?
你知道 戴夫 我想是因为你长得帅…
You know, Dave, I think it's your good looks...
因为今晚这里有些很不错的娘们
'Cause there is some fine pussy in here tonight.
把门打开 醉鬼
Open that door, rummy.
- 开门 麦克 - 快点
- Open the door, Mike. - Now.
什么时候你想被操了 跟我说一声
You ever wanna get fucked, let me know.
妈了个B的 怎么样? 现在你知道了吧
How's that, motherfucker? Now you know.
给我把脏嘴闭紧点
Keep your fucking mouths closed.
怎么 你又想放什么屁?肥猪戴夫?
What, you wanna say some shit, Fat Dave?
- 操你妈! - 操你妈!
- Fuck you! - Fuck you!
给我调杯马提尼酒 你个死胖子!
Make me a martini, you fucking fat bastard!
- 去调! - 你滚蛋
- Make it! - Get the fuck out.
给我调杯马提尼酒 弱智!
Make me a fucking martini, you fat fucking retard!
妈的真见鬼了
Fucking unbelievable.
- 找我有什么事? - 你是布里桑特侦探?
- Can I help you? - You Detective Bressant?
- 对 - 帕特里克·肯奇 刚才是你打电话吧?
- That's right. - Patrick Kenzie. Did you just call me?
哦 不好意思 我是侦查警司瑞米·布里桑特
Oh, sorry. Sergeant Detective Remy Bressant.
你好?
How you doing?
- 我们该…坐下吗? - 有什么不对劲?
- Should we... Sit down? - Something wrong?
没有!我只是…
No! I just...
我想尼克大概以为 你们的年纪应该再大点
I think Nick was expecting an older couple, maybe.
生活里充满意外
Life's full of surprises.
科温·厄尔 多次猥亵他人 前不久被允许在监外工作
Corwin Earle. Serial molester, recently work-released.
就在阿曼达失踪前后 他也溜了
Went AWOL around the time Amanda disappeared.
已知他的伙伴有利昂·特雷特
Known associates, Leon Trett
和他漂亮的老婆罗伯塔
and his handsome wife, Roberta.
特雷特夫妇分别是在六个月前 和八个月前被释放的
The Tretts were released six and eight months ago, respectively.
他们有毒瘾
They have drug habits.
我们不知道他们在哪儿 不过我们认为科温和他们在一起
We don't know where they are, but we think Corwin's with them.
监狱里有个线人说科温很信任他
Jailhouse snitch claims that Corwin confided in him
还告诉他 等自己出去时 要搬去和家人一起住
and told him when he got out, he was gonna move in with his family.
显然这三个家伙
Apparently the three of them
在玩过家家游戏
have some kind of Addams Family deal going on.
科温的计划是 在家里养个孩子当性奴
Corwin's plan is to keep a kid in the house to have sex with.
- 哦 好像很有希望实现 - 如果扯到阿曼达 就不能这么说了
- Well, that sounds promising. - Not for Amanda, it doesn't.
你们认为这就是绑架阿曼达的人?
Do you think this is who has Amanda?
唔 我们的猜想有很多漏洞
Well, there's a lot of holes in our theory.
我是说 科温喜欢的是小正太 你们知道吗?
I mean, Corwin likes little boys, you know?
他喜欢七岁到九岁的
He likes them seven or eight or nine.
这么说我们忙了三天 只搞到这点? 没别的线索了?
So that's it, that's all we got, there's no other leads, three days in?
不 也有别的
No, we got more.
有六个通灵者叫我们到六个不同的 州去找人
We got six psychics telling us to look in six different states,
我们发现莱昂内尔和碧有无懈可击的 不在场证明
we got Lionel and Bea with airtight alibis,
我们走访了方圆一英里内的每一户邻居
we've interviewed every neighbor in a mile radius
我们抓住了一个用手指猥亵妇女的囚犯
and we got a convicted finger-blaster
他刚好弄断了他的脚镣
who just happened to cut off his ankle bracelet.
- 别激动… - 不 不 不 不!
- Take it easy... - No, no, no, no, no!
这家伙以为他是谁?
Who the fuck is this guy?
你在这里是因为杰克·道伊尔 让我们对你客气点
You're here because Jack Doyle had us extend you a courtesy.
你要是有什么线索告诉我 我很欢迎
You got something to contribute, you know, be my guest.
否则的话 你…
Otherwise, hey, you...
你可以回去看你的《哈利·波特》
You know, you can go back to your Harry Potter book.
一般这种案子 都是被害人的熟人干的吧?
Isn't it usually somebody who knows the victim?
在海琳·麦克雷蒂的生活里
I think there's plenty of people in Helene McCready's life
有能力干这事的人多得很
that are capable of doing this.
那么也许你们该去找 雷·利堪斯基谈谈
So then you probably talked to Ray Likanski.
- 谁? - 雷·利堪斯基
- Who? - Ray Likanski.
他们叫他"瘦猴雷" 身高6英尺2英寸 体重160磅左右
"Skinny Ray," they call him, 6'2", about 160 pounds.
有毒瘾 是海琳的男朋友 没听说过?
Does blow. Helene's boyfriend. No?
- 没听说过这人 - 恕我冒昧
- Never heard of him. - Well, with all due respect,
我认为我们也许能提供这方面的线索
I think we might be able to contribute on that point.
- 真的?怎么回事? - 阿曼达失踪的那天晚上
- Really? How's that? - The night Amanda went missing,
瘦猴雷在菲尔莫酒馆里
Skinny Ray was down at the Fillmore Lounge
吸了大概两个钟头的粉 时间是8:00到10:00
doing coke for two hours, between 8:00 and 10:00.
真有意思
Fascinating.
- 和海琳·麦克雷蒂一起 - 你在耍我吧
- With Helene McCready. - You're shitting me.
是她把我们耍了
She did bullshit us.
我要去撕烂她的嘴
I'm gonna have to tear her a new asshole.
我在下面等你
Meet you down there.
布里桑特这个姓是什么来历?
So what kinda name is Bressant?
是路易斯安那州的姓
It's the kind they give you in Louisiana.
哦 是吗?我还以为你是本地人
Oh, yeah? Thought you were from here.
哦 这全看你怎么想
Well, it all depends on how you look at it.
比如说 你也许觉得自己比我 更有资格叫本地人
I mean, you might think that you're more from here than me, for example.
可是我在这里住的时间比你活的时间都长
But I been living here longer than you been alive.
那么谁是对的呢?
So who's right?
我会好好想想
I'll mull it over.
- 怎么样 呆鸟? - 布巴
- What's up, sucker? - Bubba.
- 见到你真好 兄弟 - 见到你真好
- Good to see you, brother. - Good to see you.
- 你过得怎样?好吗? - 好
- How you been? You been good? - Yeah.
怎么样 安姬? 你好吗 宝贝?
Yeah? What's up, Angie? How you doing, baby?
你见过这些人吗?
You seen those people?
吸毒的 吸毒的 妈的… 恋童癖
Drug addict, drug addict, fucking... Pedophile.
你凭什么认为我认识这种人?
What the fuck makes you think I know people like this?
布巴 我知道你付房租不是为了 给纳税人服务
Bub, I know you don't pay your rent doing people's taxes.
我付房租也不是为了
Yeah, I don't pay my rent selling penny rocks
卖白粉给斜白眼的恋童癖
to walleyed child molesters, neither.
他们三个不全是恋童癖
They're not all three child molesters.
只有…只有这家伙是 科温·厄尔
Just... Just this one, Corwin Earle.
另两个只是和他一起混的瘾君子
The other two are just baseheads he hangs out with.
你们俩现在算什么? 正义卫士?
What are the two of yas, crime dogs, now?
有人雇我们找那个小女孩
We got hired to find that little girl.
在孩子被绑走的时候
Turns out the mother was down at the Fillmore all night
当妈的整晚都在菲尔莫鬼混
while the kid was taken.
- 和瘦猴雷一起 - 瘦猴雷是个娘娘腔
- With Skinny Ray. - Skinny Ray is a fucking bitch.
- 我以为瘦猴雷是你的人 - 给我工作?
- I thought Ray was your boy. - Work for me?
瘦猴雷早被可卡因烧坏脑子了 他是为海地佬干的
Skinny Ray, he's a fucking cokehead. He works for the Haitian.
雷为"奶酪"工作?
Ray works for Cheese?
对 奶酪 雷 克里斯·穆伦 捡垃圾的三人帮
Yeah, Cheese, Ray, Chris Mullen, whole trash-picker crew.
你卖过东西给海琳吗?
Did you ever sell to Helene?
我现在没有在监狱里隔着厚玻璃 跟你说话
There's reasons why there ain't three inches of Plexiglas
是有原因的
between us right now.
因为我不和海琳这样的骚货扯上关系
That's 'cause I don't fuck with skeezers like Helene.
也不和奶酪这样的岛民纠缠
Or coconuts like Cheese.
现在你们该懂了
You should know better by now.
我是这烂丛林的国王
I'm the king of this motherfucking jungle.
不过要是我听到点什么 会让你知道的
I'll let you know if I hear anything, though.
- 谢谢 兄弟 - 走好
- Thanks, bro. - Peace.
你和"奶酪"让·巴普提斯熟吗?
How well do you know "Cheese" Jean Baptiste?
- 谁? - 别装了 宝贝
- Who? - Come on, sweetheart.
"奶酪"让·巴普提斯?
"Cheese" Jean Baptiste?
哦 有点耳熟
Oh, sounds familiar.
不 不 别说什么"耳熟" 海琳
No. No. It don't "sound familiar," Helene.
他是个残暴的 反社会的 海地裔罪犯 绰号"奶酪"
He's a violent, sociopathic Haitian criminal named "Cheese."
你到底认不认识他?
Either you know him or you don't.
他是什么人?
Who is he?
他是个毒贩子吧 不是吗?
He's a drug lord or something, isn't he?
海琳 他是什么人?
Helene, who is he?
- 朋友而已 莱昂内尔 - 谢谢
- He's just a guy, Lionel. - Thank you.
麦克雷蒂太太 没错 他的身份之一是毒贩
He is, among other things, Mrs. McCready, a drug dealer, yes.
- 还有什么? - 我不知道
- What other things? - I don't know.
你为什么不回答你哥哥的问题 海琳?
Why don't you answer your brother's questions, Helene?
你为什么不去吃黑鬼的鸡巴 碧?
Why don't you go suck a nigger's dick, Bea?
你给我听着! 不许对我老婆无礼
You listen to me! You don't disrespect my wife,
也不许在我的厨房里说这种 种族歧视的话
and you don't make racial remarks in my kitchen.
- 这个人是干什么的? - 这是我的厨房 莱昂内尔
- Who is this man? - It's my kitchen, Lionel.
你明白我的意思!
You know what I mean!
嘿 嘿 嘿 别激动 别激动
Hey, hey, hey. Take it easy. Take it easy.
他是个毒贩 皮条客 卖A片的 行了吧?
He's a drug dealer, a pimp, a pornographer. All right?
好极了 你和皮条客来往
Perfect. You associate with a pimp.
卖A片的?海琳
A pornographer? Helene.
我们认为他曾经在城门那里把 波奇·杰克森裹在毯子里
And we think he rolled up Pokey Jackson in a carpet
然后一枪爆了他的头 所以他又多了一条身份
and shot him in the head on Castlegate, so there's that, too.
你为他干过什么?
What do you do for him?
我只是跑腿的
I just mule.
偶尔做做 不是经常干
Occasionally, not making a habit out of it.
耶稣 玛利亚 圣约瑟啊 莱昂内尔 她这是什么意思?
Jesus, Mary and Joseph. Lionel, what does that mean?
意思是她运过毒品 碧
It means she's a drug runner, Bea. It means she carries drugs.
- 对吗 海琳? - 天哪 运过几次
- Isn't that right, Helene? - Oh, my God, a few times.
- 在哪? - 普罗维登斯…
- Where? - Providence...
这他妈的有关系吗?
Does it fucking matter?
你以为我在胡闹吗?
You think I'm fucking around, here?
你以为我在玩游戏? 这当然有关系
You think I'm playing games, here? 'Course it matters.
最好回答他的问题 海琳
Better answer his question, Helene.
- 为了什么? - 帮帮忙 莱昂内尔
- For what? - Fuck's sake, Lionel.
- 你觉得是什么呢?为了钱和嗜好呗 - 什么嗜好 毒品?
- What do you think? Money, taste. - Of what, drugs?
不 用在柜子上的鸡心小贴纸
No, little puffy heart stickers for my locker.
- 什么类型的毒品? - 可卡因和海洛因
- What kind of drugs? - Cocaine and heroin.
- 不对 那样的话我会看见她的针眼 - 如果用鼻子吸 就没有针眼了 对吗?
- No, I would've seen the track marks. - Not if you snort it. Right, sugar?
对 那样不太容易上瘾
Yeah, less addictive that way.
你真行
Piece of work.
这是干什么?你上哪儿去?
What the fuck is that? Where are you going?
哦 我一直在想我听说的一件事
Oh, yeah. I keep thinking about this thing I heard.
- 你知道我要说什么事吗? - 不知道
- You know where I'm going with this? - No.
你知道我在DCU干过吗?
Did you know I used to work DCU?
- 关我屁事 - 好
- I give a fuck. - Okay.
我现在还跟那里的几个人关系不错
So, I still know some of those guys real well.
总之我听说 在新罕布什尔
Anyway, I heard someone ripped Cheese off
有人私吞了奶酪的钱
on a New Hampshire run.
- 你听说过这事吗? - 没有
- Did you hear anything about that? - No.
- 愿意接受测谎调查吗? - 我已经做过一次了
- Care to take a polygraph? - I already took one.
这次的问题不一样
Different questions this time.
好啦 没关系的
Come on. It's all right.
几个吸毒的人互相拆台 我们才不在乎呢
We don't care about a couple of hopheads beating each other.
我们关心的是你的孩子
We care about your child.
所以快说吧
So come on.
多少?
How much?
你心里到底有没有你的孩子?
You even give a fuck about your kid?
当然有
'Course I do.
我们知道你拿了钱 告诉我们你拿了多少
And we know you took the money. So just tell us how much you took.
多少?
How much?
十三
One thirty.
- 13万美元? - 是的 碧
- $ 130,000? - Yes, Bea.
你怎么干的?
How'd you do it?
我和雷送东西去纳舒厄城 知道吧?
Me and Ray had to do this run up Nashua, right?
哦
Yeah.
我们把四公斤东西交给那些骑摩托的人
We dropped four ki's on these bikers.
在我们拿着钱走回汽车旅馆的时候
When we was walking back through the motel with all the money,
那些警察就一下冒出来 冲着骑摩托的人去了
these cops just swooped right in, went right for the bikers,
那时阿曼达和我们在一起 所以我们就假装是一家子
and Amanda was with us, so we just pretended to be like a family.
- 然后我们进了车 开溜了 - 你把阿曼达也带去了?
- And we got in the car, took off. - You took Amanda with you?
哦 你说我该怎么办? 把她丢在车里吗?
Oh, what am I gonna do? Leave her in the car, Bea?
我可没请保姆
I don't got no daycare.
当妈真不容易 养家糊口有多难 你知道吗?
It's really hard being a mother. It's hard raising a family, you know?
全靠我一个人
All on my own.
上帝让你生不出小孩 所以你是不会懂的
But God made you barren, so you wouldn't fucking know.
- 我理解你 碧 - 你这天杀的
- So I understand, Bea, okay? - You are an abomination.
- 嘿 嘿 嘿 别扯远了 - 上帝为我作证
- Hey, hey, hey. Right here. - As God is my witness.
别扯远了 后来发生了什么?
Right here. What happened next?
我们开车回去的时候 雷那个混蛋就说
We was driving back, and Ray, fucking Ray was like,
"你知道 人人都会以为 警察把钱没收了"
"You know everyone's gonna think the cops got the money."
你对奶酪说 警察把钱没收了
You told Cheese the cops got it.
可是你和雷把钱藏起来了
But you and Ray kept the money.
- 这事都是雷的错 - 海琳 现在钱在哪?
- This whole fucking thing is Ray's fault. - Where's the money now, Helene?
- 在雷那里 - 那么雷在哪?
- It's with Ray. - And where's Ray?
- 切尔西 - 咱们走 快
- Chelsea. - Let's go. Come on.
她搭你的车 我可不想让她上我的车
She rides with you. I don't want her in my car.
- 快走啊 别挡道 - 操你妈
- Go on. Move your bike! - Go fuck your mother.
- 什么… - 滚吧 呆瓜!
- What the... - Beat it, sucker!
海琳 你以前和司各特·弗拉赫 交往过 对吗?
Helene, you used to go with Scott Flaherty, didn't you?
- 你怎么知道? - 我也上过圣马克中学
- How do you know? - You know, I went to Saint Mark's.
那时我是新生 你是高年级的 你不记得我了?
I was a freshman when you were a senior. You don't remember me?
不记得
No.
司各特后来怎样了?
Whatever happened to Scott?
他捅了一个外国留学生
He stabbed a foreign exchange student in the chest.
得在沃尔波尔坐一辈子牢 现在他是基佬了
He got life in Walpole. He's a faggot now.
他在高中时就有点像基佬
He was kind of a faggot in high school.
哦 你可真够损的 他以前很可爱
Oh, man. You're terrible. He was cute.
嗯 他很适合穿紧身短裤
Well, he kind of wore them tight shorts.
哦 这么说基佬是谁? 你男朋友是基佬
Oh, who's a faggot now? You're dating a faggot.
那么… 那些钱最后怎么会到切尔西的?
So, how did the... How'd the money end up in Chelsea?
我以为你们和… 你和雷后来回家了
I thought youse and... You and Ray went home after.
不 我们先送阿曼达回家 然后回到雷的住处
No, we dropped off Amanda and went back to Ray's.
可是雷那个白痴把他的宝贝可卡因 忘在我家里了
But fucking retarded Ray left his baby rock at my place.
你知道 那时我就想: "我要甩了这个混蛋"
You know, right then, I'm like, "I'm gonna drop this motherfucker.
"我可不在乎他的屌是不是很大"
"I don't care if he does got a big dick."
我们回到公寓 雷在大喊大叫
So we went back to the apartment and Ray was hollering,
他会吵醒阿曼达的 她需要睡觉 对吧?
he was gonna wake up Amanda, she needs her sleep, you know?
所以我们又回了雷的家
So, we went back to Ray's,
- 或者说是雷他老娘的家 - 哦?
- or Ray's mother's. Whatever. - Yeah?
我不知道他老娘去哪里了 可是她把一屋子的猫都留下了
I don't know where that mother went, but she left all her fucking cats in there,
那里一股尿味
and it smells like cock.
奶酪没和你们联系过? 没给你们留口信?
And Cheese never contacted you, never left you a note?
没有 奶酪那边一点消息都没有
No. We didn't hear nothing from Cheese.
所以雷告诉我: "什么都别说"
That's why Ray said, "Don't say shit."
你不觉得为了你女儿
You didn't think it was worth it for your daughter's sake
你也应该把这事告诉别人吗? 你的孩子在奶酪手上
to tell people what happened? Cheese has your kid.
天知道他会对她做什么
God fucking knows what he's doing to her.
你说我该怎么办?
What am I gonna do?
给奶酪打电话说: "你抓了我女儿?"
Call Cheese and be like, "You got my daughter?
"因为我刚吞了你的钱 正在数呢"
"'Cause I just ripped you off, and I'm just checking."
对!
Yeah!
- 海琳 坐回去 - 哦 天哪!
- Helene, sit back. - Oh, my God!
哦 我还要给警察打电话说:
Oh, I'm gonna call the cops, too, and be like, "You know,
你们已经知道或者想知道吧? 我给人运可卡因和海洛因
"just so you know, wanna know I run coke and heroin
"这没关系吧?"
"in case that's irrelevant."
好了 冷静点 冷静点
All right, calm down. Calm down.
你让我恶心
You make me sick.
你凭什么认为 雷没有把钱都花掉?
What makes you think Ray hasn't spent all the money, Helene?
得了 钱是我藏的
Nigger, please. I hid it.
停车吧
Pull over.
看来有人先和雷谈了会儿话 然后才把他打死
Looks like somebody had a little talk with Ray before they shot him.
- 他好像挺能撑的 - 他没有
- Looks like he held out pretty good. - He didn't have it.
他没法告诉他们钱在哪里 因为他不知道
He couldn't tell them where the money was, because he didn't know.
是海琳藏的钱
Helene hid it.
雷真不会挑朋友
Ray made poor relationship choices.
我猜他们不相信他
Guess they didn't believe him.
可怜的小流氓
Poor prick.
我可不想在车里傻等
I'm not waiting in a fucking car.
- 海琳 钱在哪? - 我才不管什么钱呢
- Where's the money, Helene? - I give a fuck about the money.
- 海琳… - 我只要我女儿回家
- Helene... - I just want my daughter home with me.
我知道 我知道… 很抱歉 雷的事让你不好受 不过…
I know it. I know, I'm... I'm sorry. It's very upsetting about Ray. But...
- 钱在哪? - 就在那里
- Where's the money? - It's right there.
- 哪里? - 在雷昏过去的时候埋的
- Where? - Buried it when Ray was passed out.
那本书是讲什么的?
What was that book about,
就是那本 《你需要的一切都在你家后院里》
Everything You Need Is in Your Own Backyard?
- 我想那是本法国书 - 那不是书
- I think it was a French book. - Yeah, that wasn't a book.
- 是书 - 不对 那是漫画
- That was a book. - No, it was a cartoon.
- 去你的 - 不 是漫画
- The fuck out of here. - No, it was a cartoon.
- 对吗 海琳? - 你们俩都去死
- Right, Helene? - Fuck youse both.
我们现在该叫联邦调查局来吗?
Should we bring in the FBI at this point?
- 那是最坏的选择 - 为什么?
- That's the worst thing we could do. - Why is that?
因为我不想看到奶酪收到一包报纸
'Cause I don't wanna see Cheese kill Amanda
然后一气之下杀了阿曼达
after he opens a bag full of newspapers.
这是绑架案
It's kidnapping.
- 我没看见勒索的纸条 你看见吗? - 没有 没有纸条
- I don't see a note. You see a note? - Nope. No note.
我们现在调查的是儿童失踪案
We're investigating a missing children's case, here.
这跟绑架没关系 要想让阿曼达回家 最快的办法是
Kidnapping has nothing to do with it. Fastest way to get Amanda home
找到奶酪 用钱换人 然后回来
is go to Cheese, swap the money for her and walk away.
- 简单明了 - 你了解奶酪吗?
- Plain and simple. - Do you know Cheese?
我更了解他兄弟裘德 他是个可爱的家伙
Knew his brother better, Jude. He was a sweet kid.
奶酪和他正相反
Cheese went another way.
- 他不会伤害她吧? - 去问雷吧
- He wouldn't hurt her, right? - Ask Ray.
好吧 听我说 他只关心他的钱
All right, listen. All he cares about is his money.
要是他能讨回钱… 他就不会伤害阿曼达
If he gets it back... He's not gonna hurt Amanda.
你别废话了 好吗? 我们会把她领回来的 不会有事
Just keep your mouth shut, okay? We'll get her back. It'll be fine.
- 你要去和他谈? - 对 我就是这意思
- Oh, you're gonna talk to him? - Yeah, that's the idea.
好吧 你跟他说我很抱歉 好吗?
Okay. Well, tell him I'm sorry, all right?
他认识我 你就跟他说 我给他赔不是了
I mean, he knows me, just tell him I apologize.
对 这样肯定都能摆平了 只要带她回家就行了
Yeah, I'm sure that'll fix everything. Just take her home.
- 这事就交给我们了 好吗? - 我们在那里和你们碰头
- We'll take care of this, all right? - We'll meet you over there.
我饿
I'm hungry.
好吧 我给你找点吃的 海琳
All right. I'll get you something, Helene.
不 是她
No, her.
这是我抱她上床前 她对我说的话
That's what she said to me right before I put her to bed.
她说: "我饿" 他们会给她吃饭的 对吗?
She said, "I'm hungry." I mean, they fed her, right?
她现在该不饿了吧?
She's not still hungry?
我不知道
I don't know.
我知道我闯祸了
I know I fucked up.
我只要女儿回来
I just want my daughter back.
我对天发誓 再也不吸毒了
I swear to God, I won't use no drugs no more.
再也不出门了 我会做个正派女人
I won't even go out, I'll be fucking straight.
我说的是真话
Cross my heart.
好了 我们会找到她的 海琳
It's all right. We're gonna find her, Helene.
你一定要找到她 你保证?
You have to. You promise?
好 我会尽力的 我会的
Yeah. I'm gonna try. I will.
你要保证 你要向我保证
Promise. You have to promise me.
我保证
I promise.
好了
All right.
你们这是打算上哪儿去?
Where do you think you're going?
和奶酪谈谈
Talk to Cheese.
不 你们不用去 回车里去
No, you're not. No, get back in the car.
不对 这是错的 他绝不会和当差的人说话
No, that's a mistake. He's never gonna talk to a badge.
- 不行 没门 - 事关重大
- No. No way. - It's too important.
你们到底想不想让那女孩回来?
You wanna get the girl back, or not?
我了解他 要想找中介人和他谈交易
I know him. If there's a deal to be brokered,
- 我们就是最好的人选 - 不 让我和尼克来料理这事
- we're the ones who can do it. - No, me and Nick are handling this.
你们回车里去
Get back in the car.
朋友 要是你们俩进去谈小女孩的赎金
Guys, you two go in there and negotiate a ransom for a little girl,
就和联邦调查局没啥两样了 因为这就是绑架
then it is the FBI. 'Cause it's kidnapping.
你们只会吓着他
All you're gonna do is scare him.
你们把他吓得越厉害 小姑娘就越惨
The more you scare him, the worse it is for her.
好吧 去吧
All right. Go ahead.
你们就休息一下 等着吧 我了解他 交给我吧
Just fucking relax, sit tight. I know him. I'm gonna take care of it.
祝你好运
Good luck.
好久不见了
It's been a long time.
不用 我戒了
No. I quit.
我要说点私事
I'm gonna talk some private shit.
- 不用等我 不过也别走太远 - 你知道我会留在这儿的
- Don't wait, but don't get too far. - You know I'll be right here.
娘们喜欢切达奶酪
Bitches love the cheddar.
- 克里斯 你混得怎样? - 比你强
- How you been, Chris? - Better than you.
听你这么说我很高兴
Yeah. Good to hear it.
- 我操你 - 老弟 悠着点
- Fuck you. - Man, be cool.
很久没见到傻瓜了
It's been too long not to see a fool.
我愿意听一听
I grant you audience.
说吧
Go.
我们找到了你在切尔西要找的东西
We found what you were looking for in Chelsea.
我在切尔西要找什么?
What I care about Chelsea?
有个住在那里的白痴吞了你的钱
'Cause one of the idiots that robbed you lived there.
哪个白痴?
What idiot?
被你和克里斯用铁管打 然后一枪崩了的白痴
The one that you and Chris beat with a pipe and shot in the chest.
我不知道有人被杀了
I don't know about nobody getting kill.
不过要是有人吞了我的钱 后来死掉的话…
But if somebody rob me and end up dead...
那么 你也知道 生活就是王八蛋
Well, you know, life is a motherfucker.
奶酪 我们找到了你的钱 就埋在雷的后院里
Cheese, we got your money. It was buried in Ray's backyard.
我们要用它跟你换 阿曼达·麦克雷蒂
We wanna give it back to you in exchange for Amanda McCready.
除了我们 只有外面的两个警察知道这事
The two police outside are the only other people who know.
你做的事没人在乎
No one gives a fuck about what you did.
我是说 我也没那么喜欢雷
I mean, I didn't even like Ray that much.
你要拿回你的钱 当妈的要找回自己的女儿
You're gonna get your money, the mother gets her daughter back,
我们会说孩子是在灌木丛里找到的
and we'll say we found the kid in the bushes, or whatever.
要么这样私了 只有你知我知
It's either this, real quiet,
要么我叫一千个警察来踢破你的门
or it's a thousand fucking cops kicking your door in,
用他们的大膝盖压着你的脖子
putting their fat knees in your neck.
等一下
Hold up.
Whoa. Whoa.
这是干什么?
What the fuck is this?
把你的T恤掀起来
Lift up your shirt.
- 别来这套 老兄 - 操你妈 听到没有
- Come on, man. - Motherfucker, you heard me.
把你的T恤掀起来
Lift up your shirt.
- 不是这样的 奶酪 - 宝贝 我不跟你玩
- It ain't like that, Cheese. - My CC, I ain't down with you.
把你的T恤掀起来
Lift up your shirt.
你也是 男女都一样
You, too, baby. Ain't no gender immunity.
让我看见奶头
Let me see some tit.
到我的地盘来就别耍这种花样
Don't ever come in my spot like that.
你们要是找到了我的钱
You got my money,
就把它放在外面的邮箱里 听明白了吗?
you leave that shit in the mailbox on your ass way out, you feel me?
有些混蛋被傻瓜偷了钱只会干瞪眼
Some other motherfuckers let fool rob on them.
我会来真的 但不乱来
I don't play scrimmage.
我不会找小孩的麻烦
But I don't fuck with no kids.
要是那女孩的唯一希望就是你 我会为她祈祷
And if that girl only hope is you, well, I pray for her,
因为她没了 宝贝
'cause she's gone, baby.
没了
Gone.
奶酪 你要是再敢对她这样无礼
Cheese, if you ever disrespect her again like that,
我就宰了你
I'm gonna pull your fucking card.
明白吗?
Okay?
你说不是你干的 很好
So you're saying you didn't do it, fine.
我们会带上你的钱走路
We'll take your money, and we'll be on our way.
要是我们发现你在撒谎
But if it turns out you're lying,
我会把那笔钱里的每一个子儿 都用来玩死你
I'm going to spend every nickel of that money to fuck you up.
我会给警察塞钱 让他们追你
I'm gonna bribe cops to go after you,
我会出钱叫人来对付你那些没用的手下
I'm gonna pay guys to go after your weak fucking crew,
我会告诉我认识的每一个人 你是警察的线人 出卖朋友的家伙
and I'm gonna tell everyone I know that you're a CI and a rat.
我认识的人可多得很
And I know a lot of people.
到那时 你就会后悔没听我的话
And after that, you're gonna wish you had listened to me,
因为你们帮派用来做老巢的 这个破台球厅
'cause your shitty, pool-hall, crime-syndicate headquarters
会被翻个底朝天
is gonna get raided.
你那些嗑饱药的姘头会被送回老挝去
And your doped-up bitches are gonna get sent back to Laos,
这里的这个弱智为了减刑 会作证指控你
and this fucking retard right here is gonna be testifying against you
而你会在你的牢房里被一帮白人
for a reduced sentence while you're getting cornholed in your cell
操得死去活来
by a gang of crackers.
因为我听说
'Cause from what I heard,
杀小孩的人都会被送到康科德的监狱去
you guys that get sent up Concord for killing kids,
生活就是王八蛋
life a motherfucker.
再让我看到你 我就要对你动粗了
If I see you again, I'm gonna get discourteous on you.
叫那个警察也滚蛋
And get that sausage off my lawn.
- 怎么样了? - 他说他什么也不知道
- Well, what happened? - He said he didn't know anything,
不过要是你们找到了他的钱 可以放在他的邮箱里
but if you had his money, you could put it in his mailbox.
- 他就跟你说了这些? - 就这些
- That's what he told you? - That's it.
没别的了?
Nothing else?
有 他还说要你们俩滚出他的地盘
Yeah. He said that he wanted you two off his lawn.
你好象说过你认识这家伙
I thought you said you knew this fucking guy.
他认识的人有一半是人渣
Half the guys he knows are degenerates.
对 你知道另一半是什么吗?
Yeah, you know what the other half are?
- 是什么? - 警察 别拿这事来责怪我
- What? - Cops. Don't hold it against me.
不 不 我不会拿这事来责怪你
No, no. I won't hold it against you.
知道我要拿什么事来责怪你吗?
You know what I'll hold against you?
我们有过一次做成交易的机会 你说你认识他
We had one chance to make this deal. You said you knew him.
你说你能办到 但是你办砸了
You said you could do it and you fucked it up.
现在我只好去申请窃听许可 开始侦查
Now I gotta get a warrant for a tap, start surveillance,
希望老天让我们走运
hope to Christ we get lucky.
你知道 要是阿曼达因此丧了命
You know, if Amanda dies because of this,
我也不用拿这事来责怪你
I won't have to hold it against you.
你自己也会内疚很久的
You'll hold it against yourself for a long, long time.
但愿我们没把这事搞砸
Hope we didn't fuck this up.
- 喂 - 奶酪来了电话
- Yeah. - Cheese called in.
说他愿意拿阿曼达作交易 不过要在今晚
Says he'll take the deal with Amanda, but he wants to go tonight.
- 太好了 - 也好也不好
- Great. - Well, it is and it isn't.
如今警局的电话都有录音
They record calls at the station now.
- 杰克拿到了记录 - 什么意思?
- Jack got a hold of the transcript. - What does that mean?
意思是说 我们的警徽现在差不多 要被没收了
It means our badges are basically fucking forfeit at this point.
他要你们俩马上过来
He wants you both down here, now.
哦 还有 奶酪说他在邮箱里 留了点东西
Oh, and, hey, Cheese said he left something in a mailbox
可以证明阿曼达在他手上
to prove that he's got Amanda.
身为警察的被害儿童父亲发誓 不让悲剧重演
这是今天早上一段电话录音的抄本
This is a transcript of a recorded call that came in this morning.
读读重点标出的那段好吗?
Care to read the highlighted portion?
大声点
Aloud?
唔
Uh.
来电者: 妈的 你们最好有我的钱
"Caller: Bitch, you better have my money.
布里桑特侦探: 你是谁?
"Detective Bressant: Who is this?
来电者: 你知道我是谁 笨蛋…
"The caller: You know who the fuck this is, fool...
海地语粗话 如果你们想要回那女孩
"Creole curse words. If you want that girl back,
今晚就来昆西找我
"you need to meet me up Quincy tonight.
只要迟了一分钟 我就把那女孩扔进湖里
"Fuck around for a minute and I'll throw that girl in the lake."
他说的湖是指废采石场里的水潭
The lake he refers to is the water in the abandoned quarry.
布里桑特侦探未经授权
Detective Bressant goes on to make an unauthorized ransom arrangement
就打算在那个地方用13万美元
to exchange Amanda McCready for $ 130,000 tonight
赎回阿曼达·麦克雷蒂
in just that location.
经过一番讨论以后 布里桑特侦探好心地交出了
After some discussion, Detective Bressant was kind enough
这个东西
to produce this.
认识吗?
Recognize it?
你们四个人既没有通知我 也没有得到我的允许
The four of you have involved me in an illegal activity
就把我卷进了一桩非法活动 我可不喜欢这样
without my knowledge or consent, and I don't fucking appreciate it.
- 你没必要参与 长官 - 我不参与才怪
- You don't have to be a part of it, sir. - The hell I don't.
既然已经谈妥 我现在阻挠的话
If I delay this now, after this agreement,
只会进一步增加那孩子的生命危险
I just further endanger the life of that child.
你是不是觉得我会这么做?
Does that sound like something you expect me to do?
不 长官
No, sir.
上次去谈判的是我 我会承担责任的
I went in there. I'll accept responsibility.
你什么也承担不了!
You'll accept nothing!
别在这里逞英雄 小子
Don't come in here trying to get noble, boy.
让我看看那个纸条
Let me see that note.
我的天
My God.
他想把我们分开
He wants to separate us.
这纸条上说你们应该在东岸等阿曼达
The note instructs you guys to be on the east side and wait for Amanda,
我和尼克带着钱去边上的空地
me and Nick to be at the clearing by the edge with the money.
你们一接到阿曼达 马上用对讲机通知我们
Once Amanda's turned over to you, you give us a call on the radio,
我们就给钱
we turn over the cash.
- 他可能带谁来? - 克里斯·穆伦
- Who's he likely to bring with him? - Chris Mullen.
我们讨价还价时 他在那夜总会
He was at the club when we made the offer.
你对他有什么了解?
What do you know about him?
很可能是他替奶酪杀了雷
It was probably him who killed Ray for Cheese.
如果我只能猜的话
If I had to guess.
好吧 没有其他人知道这件事 对吗?
All right. Nobody else knows about this, right?
- 我不知道 - 唔?
- I don't know. - Yes?
我想问 这样私了 是对阿曼达更好 还是对我们更好?
I'm asking if keeping it quiet is better for Amanda or is it better for us?
你有孩子吗 杰纳罗小姐?
Do you have any children, Miss Gennaro?
没 长官
No, sir.
我的独生女被杀了 她才12岁 你听说过吗?
My only child was murdered. She was 12. Did you hear about it?
有些东西你可能没有听过
What you probably didn't hear,
我也希望你永远不用面对
and what I hope you never have to deal with,
是那种事情给人的感受 杰纳罗小姐 那是我不得不面对的
Miss Gennaro, is what that feels like. What I have to deal with.
明明知道我的小女儿可能死
Knowing that my little girl likely died
哭喊着要我去救她
crying out for me to come and save her.
我没有去
And I never did.
我的小女儿怀着惧怕 孤零零地死在一条浅水沟的边上
My little girl died afraid and alone in a shallow ditch bank
就在离我家不到10分钟远的路边
by the side of the road not 10 minutes from my house.
我知道失去一个孩子是什么感觉
I know what it feels like to lose a child.
现在 该死的 你们逼我出手
Now, damn it, you force my hand
还怀疑我的处理方式
and then you question the way I handle it.
没有人怀疑你 长官
No one's questioning you, sir.
我组建这个部门就是为了纪念孩子
I honor my child with this division.
为了不让别的父母经历我的遭遇
So that no parent has to go through what I've known.
这个孩子
This child.
现在就是我关心的一切
That's all I care about.
我要把她带回家
I'm gonna bring her home.
为什么他让我们大老远地到这里?
Why'd he bring us all the way up here?
我不知道 这里很大 很暗 容易逃跑
I don't know. It's big. It's dark. It's easy to get away.
不
No.
他们打算杀了她
They're gonna kill her.
这些混蛋应该上别的地方找些平地
This asshole could've found some level fucking ground somewhere.
我们就在这里分开 你们要到悬崖顶上
This is where we part ways. You guys'll be on top of that cliff.
我们就在你们对面
We'll be right across from you.
你们接到她就用对讲机通知我们
Give us a call on the radio when you have her.
- 会的 - 好的 好运
- We will. - Well, good luck.
我们走
Let's go.
他们要怎么把阿曼达带上来?
How are they gonna get Amanda up here?
有埋伏!有埋伏!
Ambush! Ambush!
嘿 瑞米!该死的奶酪! 她在哪?
Hey, Remy! Fucking Cheese! Where is she?
她在那 我看到她了 不该这样的!
There she is. I can see her. It ain't the way it is!
有人打中了奶酪!
Someone hit Cheese!
- 你确定你听到什么了? - 是的!
- You sure you heard something? - Yes!
- 在那里! - 发生了什么?
- Over there! - What happened?
我不知道 我听到水花四溅 在下面!
I don't know. I heard a splash. Down there!
有人打死了奶酪
Somebody took Cheese out,
- 然后就乱成一锅粥了 - 阿曼达在哪里?
- and then all hell broke loose. - Where's Amanda?
- 有人从那里开的枪 - 我不知道!
- Shots were fired from over there. - I don't know!
有东西掉水里了
Something went in the water!
- 什么? - 你确定你听到了?
- What? - You sure you heard something?
- 是的 有东西掉进去了 但我… - 它去哪了?
- Yeah, something went in, but I... - Where did it go?
那里!就在那!
There! Right there!
哦 天哪
Oh, my God.
哦 不
Oh, no.
上帝啊
Jesus Christ!
呼叫高斯本医生 高斯本医生请移步重症监护室
Paging Dr. Goldsburn. Dr. Goldsburn to ICU.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
- 腿怎么样? - 还好
- How's the leg? - It'll be fine.
他们找到什么了吗?
They find anything?
- 潜水员正在那里找 - 她可能还活着
- They got divers in there now. - She could still be alive.
也许她躲起来了 她可能吓得不敢动
Maybe she's hiding. She could be stuck.
对吗?
Right?
我想不是
I don't think so.
嘿…
Hey...
只要它存在一天 就会继续看护着
He's ever seen in all his years,
一个叫阿曼达的小女孩和 一个叫米拉贝尔的布娃娃
on a little girl called Amanda and a doll named Mirabelle.
这个采石场的水潭深不见底 凶险莫测
This quarry is extremely deep and treacherous.
被它吞噬的东西往往是永远沉沦其中
All too often, she keeps that which she takes in.
一个悲惨的结局 苏珊
A sad end to that story, Suzanne.
的确是 菲尔
It sure is, Phil.
接下来由罗恩报道体育新闻 今晚棕熊队有比赛吗?
And Ron is next with sports. The Bruins in action tonight?
是的 菲尔
Yes, they are, Phil.
棕熊队今晚挑战飞人队
The B's took a crack at the Flyers tonight,
双方从第一节开始就杀得难分难解
and the rough stuff started in the first period.
就这样 她没了
And like that, she was gone.
我们交待了自己知道的情况 尼克和瑞米也一样
We gave our statements. Nick and Remy the same.
我们都没有为阿曼达的死受到责备
All of us spared any blame for Amanda's death.
杰克·道伊尔辞了职 他为此提出的条件是
Jack Doyle resigned on the condition
让他一个人承担所有责任
that he and he alone be held accountable.
致力于救助儿童的传奇警监
The legendary captain of a unit dedicated to children
在一番争论后引退了
stepped down today in the aftermath of controversy.
他被授予提早退休的资格
He was granted the dignity of early retirement.
但代价是退休金减半
But the humiliation of half a pension.
对于辉煌半生的他来说 这是个难堪的结局
It was an ignominious end to an illustrious career.
据他们说 克里斯在逃跑一天半后
Chris' run lasted a day and a half until, from what they could tell,
遇到了一个比他更需要钱的人
he ran into someone who wanted the money more than he did.
克里斯·穆伦 29岁
Twenty-nine-year-old Chris Mullen
昨晚被枪杀
was gunned down last night
原因显然是遭遇抢劫
in an apparent robbery.
警方负责人辩解说 最近层出不穷的罪案
The police commissioner defended the rising tide of crime
是失业率和湿度上升引起的
as a statistical aberration tied to growing unemployment
统计意义上的反常现象…
and the humidity of...
在觉得时间够长以后 他们中止了搜寻工作
Enough time went by and they called off the search.
他们给海琳发了死亡证明
They issued Helene a death certificate.
像框和小棺材是殡仪馆捐赠的
The frame and the casket were donated by the funeral home,
但是在黄昏前要归还
but had to be returned at the end of the afternoon.
你知道我爱你 对吗?
You know I love you, right?
对
Yeah.
我只是想一个人呆一会儿
I just wanna be alone for a while.
我不知道她是责怪我还是责怪自己
I don't know if she blamed me or if she blamed herself.
但是 当她以为我不在家时
But when she didn't think I was home,
或者是她以为我听不见时
or if she thought I couldn't hear,
她会啜泣
she would cry.
我情不自禁地在脑海中 一遍又一遍回想这件事
I couldn't stop running it over and over and over in my mind,
朦胧而依稀地怀疑着
the vague and distant suspicion
我们也许从来没有弄明白那晚的事情
that we never understood what happened that night,
以及我们是什么角色
what our role was.
或者事情就是这样 就像每年数以百计的
Or maybe it was just that, like the hundreds of other children
人间蒸发的孩童一样
who disappear each year and never return...
再也找不到的阿曼达 愈加萦绕在人们心头
Amanda was even more haunting for never being found.
真正被他们找到的 是又一条大新闻
What they did find was another big story,
我不禁觉得很奇怪
and I couldn't help but find it strange.
不到两个月 就在不远的地方 又有一个孩子失踪了
Not two months later and not far away, another child went missing.
…社区巡逻队成立了
...and community watch patrols are being formed.
一辆自行车被丢在路边 一个轮子不停地转
A bicycle left roadside. A tire left spinning.
最新消息
Late-breaking news on that story.
记者相信
Little Johnny Pietro is also wearing
小强尼·彼特罗的着装有标记
what this reporter believes might be a sign.
他戴着一个圣克里斯托弗的徽章
Johnny Pietro was wearing the medallion of St. Christopher,
这是守护圣徒…
patron saint of...
强尼·彼特罗和他的徽章
Johnny Pietro and his medallion.
我觉得不奇怪的是
What I didn't find strange was this time,
这一次没有他的亲戚来敲我的门
no relatives came knocking on our door.
- 嘿 帕特里克 - 嗨
- Hey, Patrick. - Hi.
- 我要你开车跟我来 - 去哪?
- I need you to come on a ride with me. - Where?
到埃弗雷特
To Everett.
- 怎么 在林恩没有聚会吗? - 真好笑
- What, no parties in Lynn? - Funny.
- 你带着你的家伙吧 对吗? - 我的什么?
- You got your toast with you, right? - My what?
你的枪 傻瓜
Your gun, dummy.
对
Yeah.
这次不是林恩的脱衣舞俱乐部 帕特里克
This ain't no strip-clubbing in Lynn, Patrick.
我有更好的给你 伙计
I got something better for you, buddy.
你叫我帮你找些人
You asked me to find some people for you.
我想我找到他们了
I think I found them.
你要带我进什么地方?
What you getting me into?
你不再追查科温·厄尔了吗?
You don't give a fuck about this Corwin Earle dude no more?
那个肥婊子和那个老甲鱼就在那里
Yo, 'cause the fat bitch and the old dude are in there.
我的人不知道那个恋童癖的下落
My man didn't know about the diddler.
和我一起进去 给我打掩护
Come in with me. Watch my side.
我们会查明那个王八蛋是不是也在
We'll find out if this motherfucker's in there.
你知道吗 帕特里克?
You know what, Patrick?
如果你不想进去 你不必进去
If you don't wanna come in, you don't have to come in.
如果你不想进去 就算了
If you don't wanna come in, fuck it.
走吧
Let's go.
猜下是谁?
Guess who?
- 杰罗姆·米勒? - 不 是白粉大仙来了
- Jerome Miller? - No, it's the coke fairy.
- 开门 - 我的钱在这里
- Open up. - I got the money right here.
老狗 你想在这该死的门口给我钱?
Marmaduke, you think you're gonna hand me money on a fucking porch?
开门
Open the door.
他是谁?
Who's he?
他是你老爹 快开门!
He's your father. Open the fucking door!
- 当心 - 好 伙计!
- Look out. - Okay, man!
别激动!别激动!
Chill! Chill!
你们成立了一支乐队?
What are you guys, starting a band?
没有人成立乐队
No one's starting a band.
试下这个
It's a taste.
老头用的可卡因
Cocaine for the old man.
该死的
Fucking Christ.
你还要我帮你把这些零钱换成整的?
Want me to change a roll of quarters for you, too?
我告诉过你 他们来这的时候要跟我说
I told you to tell me when they got here!
他们刚来
They just got here.
- 你已经吸了一些 - 这是给我尝味道的
- You already did some! - It was a taste bag.
对不起 亲爱的
Sorry, love.
数一下这叠钱
Here, count this fucking mess.
剩下的在哪 伙计?
Where's the rest, man?
他数完你给我的钱就给你
As soon as he's finished counting that fucking mess you gave me.
- 米勒先生 对不起? - 没关系
- Mr. Miller, do you mind? - No, I don't mind.
- 打扰你一下! - 你已经打扰了
- Excuse me! - You're excused.
- 嘿 请不要到处乱晃 先生 - 嘿 帅哥 别在意
- Hey, please don't snoop around, sir. - Hey, relax, handsome.
对不起!
Excuse me!
你这是要去哪里?
Where the fuck you think you're going?
米勒先生 我警告你!
Mr. Miller, I'm warning you!
停下!
Stop!
帕特里克 开枪打她
Patrick, shoot this bitch.
你个肥婊子
You fat busted cunt.
你既然用枪指着我 最好有胆开枪
You put a gun on me, you better use it.
把白粉给我!
Just give us the fucking wizza!
你不想开枪打她吗 帕特里克?
You don't wanna shoot her, Patrick?
这个人是谁?
Who's this guy?
科温!回你的房间去
Corwin! Go back to your room!
不是聚会吗?
It's not a party?
不是聚会
No, it's not a party.
有多少钱 帕特里克?
How much money's there, Patrick?
够了
Enough.
想要这个?
Want this?
你在干什么?拿好钱
What are you doing? Pick up the fucking money.
房子里至少两支枪 罗伯塔的枪是随身带着的
At least two guns in the house. Roberta's carrying hers.
- 还有什么? - 他们很兴奋
- What else? - Well, they're definitely high.
- 为什么? - 因为可卡因
- On what? - Cocaine.
这也是你朋友告诉你的?
Your friend tell you that, too?
特警小组5分钟后到
SWAT'll be here in five minutes.
你不打算等他们?
You're not gonna wait for them?
你有没有告诉我你看见科温·厄尔
Did you or did you not tell me you saw Corwin Earle
手腕上戴着圣克里斯托弗的徽章?
with the medallion of St. Christopher around his fucking wrist?
我确实看到了科温·厄尔
I definitely saw Corwin Earle.
我们不能等了
We're not waiting.
呆在这 不要乱动 好吗?
Stay here. And don't fuck around, all right?
干得好
Good job.
该死的
Fuck.
有一个…警官…有人开枪! 一个警官被击倒…枪击…
An... An officer... Shots are fired! An officer down... Shots...
听我说!
Listen to me!
一个警官在日耳曼路33号遭到枪击!
A police officer has been shot at 33 German Road!
滚开 别碰他!
Get away from him!
那是个意外
It was an accident.
是意外
等一下!
Wait!
嘿
Hey.
你还好吧?
You okay?
他们告诉我发生了什么
They told me what happened.
我为你感到骄傲
I'm proud of you.
那个人杀了一个孩子
That man killed a child.
他没权活着
He had no right to live.
- 你为我感到骄傲? - 当然
- You're proud of me? - Of course I am.
你做了你该做的
You did what you had to do.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
我想在这呆一会儿
I gotta stay here awhile.
- 我回家等你 - 好
- See you at home. - Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
一团糟 对吗?
It was fucked up, right?
他们和你说过尼克的情况吗?
They tell you anything about Nick?
他们说他会没事
They said he could be okay.
我不知道
I don't know.
他们说那个男孩多大?
They say how old that little boy was?
7岁
Seven.
二年级
Second grade.
你应该感到自豪 大部分人只会呆在外面
Should be proud of yourself. Most guys would've stayed outside.
我不知道
I don't know.
你不知道什么?
What don't you know?
我的神父告诉我 羞耻就是上帝说你做错了
My priest says shame is God telling you what you did was wrong.
去他的
Fuck him.
杀人是罪
Murder's a sin.
要看你杀的是谁
Depends on who you do it to.
你这是不择手段 只求结果
That's not how it works. It is what it is.
我曾经栽赃陷害过一个人
I planted evidence on a guy once,
那是在95年
back in '95.
我们每缴获三克半毒品 就给线人100美元
We were paying $ 100 an eight-ball to snitches.
我们的朋友雷·利堪斯基 给我们打了个电话
We got a call from our pal, Ray Likanski.
当时他找不到可以揭发的人了
He couldn't find enough guys to rat out.
总之 他告诉我们 在哥伦比亚角那边
Anyway, he tells us there's a guy pumping up in an apartment
有个人在公寓里卖白粉
up in Columbia Point.
我们进去了 我和尼克
We go in, me and Nicky.
15年前 尼克上阵的时候 可不是开玩笑的
Fifteen years ago, when Nicky went in, it was no joke.
那里…是个仓库一样的房子
So, it's a... It's a stash house, right?
那个老太婆被打翻在地 她丈夫很卑鄙 突然出现
The old lady's beat to shit, the husband's mean, cracked out,
想给我们制造麻烦 尼克把他撂倒
tries to give us trouble, Nicky lays him down.
我们搜查了一下 但是感觉我们是搞错了
We're doing an inventory, but it looks like we messed up
因为屋里没有毒品 接着我走进了后面的房间
because there's no dope in the house, and I go in the back room...
我要说明一下 那个地方像狗窝
Now, this place was a shithole, mind you.
老鼠 蟑螂都处都是
Rats, roaches all over the place.
但是在后面 孩子的卧室里
But the kid's room, in the back,
却一尘不染
was spotless.
不 我是说 他经常打扫 拖地 干净得无可挑剔
No, I mean, he swept it, mopped it, it was immaculate.
小男孩坐在床上
The little boy's sitting on the bed
死死抱着他的PlayStation
holding onto his PlayStation for dear life.
脸上毫无表情
There's no expression on his face,
眼泪流个不停
tears streaming down.
他想告诉我他刚学会九九乘法表
He wants to tell me he just learned his multiplication tables.
天哪
Christ.
我是说 他父亲把他扔在一个狗窝里
I mean, the father's got him in this crack den,
只给他吃小蛋糕 还打他屁股
subsisting on Twinkies and ass-whippings,
这个孩子仅仅希望有人夸他干得不错
and this little boy just wants someone to tell him that he's doing a good job.
你对天主教感到过疑惑吗?
You're worried what's Catholic?
我是说 孩子们只会宽恕
I mean, kids forgive.
孩子们不会审判
Kids don't judge.
孩子们把另一边脸也给你打
Kids turn the other cheek.
他们这样做 得到的是什么?
What do they get for it?
所以 我走了回去
So I went back out there,
我在起居室的地板上放了一盎司海洛因
I put an ounce of heroin on the living room floor,
我把那个当爸爸的送去坐牢 七到九年
and I sent the father on a ride, seven to nine.
- 那样做对吗? - 太他妈对了
- That was the right thing? - Fucking A!
你总得选一边
You gotta take a side.
要是你猥亵儿童 殴打儿童
You molest a child, you beat a child,
你就不是我这一边的
you're not on my side.
如果你看见我来 你最好跑
If you see me coming, you better run,
因为我要干死你
because I am gonna lay you the fuck down!
放松
Easy.
不觉得轻松
Don't feel easy.
没有父亲 这个孩子是不是过得更好?
Is the kid better off without his father?
对
Yeah.
但是 说不定他正在贩毒
But okay, I mean, could be out there right now,
腰里还插着把手枪
pumping with a gun in his waistband.
这是一场战争 伙计
It's a war, man.
我们占了上风吗?
Are we winning?
没有
No.
你还会再做一次吗? 会打死科温·厄尔吗?
Would you do it again? Clip Corwin Earle?
不
No.
那样你就对了吗?
Does that make you right?
嗯?
Hmm?
我不知道
I don't know.
不过那样也不能算错 对吗?
Doesn't make it wrong, though, does it?
- 嘿 - 嗨
- Hey. - Hi.
瑞米怎么样?
How's Remy?
他骗了我
He lied to me.
以前跟瑞米提起雷的时候 他怎么说?
What did Remy say about Ray back in Roxbury?
- 从没听说过他 - 从没听说过他
- Never heard of him. - Never heard of him.
现在他说雷向他告密有15年了
Now he says Ray's been snitching for him for 15 years.
他叫他老朋友
He called him his "old pal."
还说他都找不到可以揭发的人了
Said he couldn't find enough people to snitch out.
帕特里克…
Patrick...
都是由于雷·利堪斯基 阿曼达才被抓
And Ray Likanski is the reason Amanda got taken in the first place,
瑞米撒谎说不认识他
and Remy lies about knowing him.
算了吧
Let it go.
他为什么要撒谎? 他要隐瞒什么?
Why would he lie? What's he have to hide?
阿曼达死了
Amanda's dead.
算了吧
Let it go.
亲爱的
Babe.
尼克死了
Nick died.
左 左
Left. Left.
肯奇先生
Mr. Kenzie.
科温·厄尔那件事 你干得好
Nice fucking job on Corwin Earle.
阿门
Amen.
- 关于尼克 请节哀 - 好 谢谢
- Sorry about Nick. - Yeah, thanks.
我想了想那天晚上我们的对话
I was thinking about our conversation the other night.
我说了些不该说的
Well, I said some things I shouldn't have.
你知道 我喝多了
You know, too much rum.
哦 哪些话你不该说?
Yeah, like what?
今天不要烦我 帕特里克
Don't fuck with me, Patrick. Not today.
哦 我不想找你麻烦
Oh, I wouldn't fuck with you.
哦 你想这样玩?好吧
Oh, you wanna play it like that, huh? Okay.
忘了那晚的事 我们会成为朋友
Forget about the other night, and we'll be friends.
如果我不呢?
What if I don't?
那不是一个你想要的"如果"
That's not an "if" you wanna bring into your life.
上周和他吃了饭
Had lunch with him last week.
达纳上周和他吃了饭?
Dana had lunch with him last week?
失陪了
Excuse me.
嘿 德弗
Hey, Dev.
- 嘿 如何? - 很好 你呢?
- Hey, how you doing? - All right, how you been?
还不错
I can't complain.
- 能和你聊几句吗? - 可以
- Can I talk to you? - Yeah.
这里不方便
Not here.
如果是这样 那你要请我吃午饭了
If it's like that, then you're gonna have to buy me lunch.
- 去查特豪斯餐馆吧 半小时后? - 可以
- How's the Chart House, half hour? - Sounds about right.
嘿 瑞米原来和你一起缉毒 对吗?
Hey, Remy used to work Narcotics with you, right?
DCU（缉毒部门） 对 怎么了?
DCU, yeah. What's up?
他为什么离开?
Why'd he leave?
他老是会把别人惹毛
Had a habit of just rubbing people the wrong way.
怎么说?他做了什么?
Like what? What'd he do?
比如 和一个妓女结婚
Like marry a prostitute, for one.
别这样
Come on.
如果你是警察 不可能做这种事 对吗?
Might not wanna do that if you're a cop, right?
就算你是水管工 也不可能做这种事
Might not wanna do that if you're a plumber.
那么 发生了什么?
So, what happened?
他说他爱她 叫迈克·斯耐尔别管闲事
He says he loves her, tells Mike Snell to go fuck himself,
然后就申请了转调
and puts in for a transfer.
怎么 调到道伊尔那里?
What, to Doyle?
72年 是道伊尔把 瑞米从路易斯安那带过来的
Doyle brought Remy from Louisiana, back in '72.
不过你不认为瑞米有污点 是吗?
You don't think that Remy's dirty, though, do you?
什么污点?
What's "dirty"?
- 我知道他有次栽赃害人 - 哦 你知道?
- I know he planted evidence once. - Oh, you do?
对 怎么?
Yeah. Why?
瞧 伙计 CSI这部电视剧 可把我们害惨了
Look, man. CSI is killing us out here.
每个陪审员 都希望我们找到微纤维啥的
Every other juror, all they wanna know is where the microfibers are.
我们是干活的
Certain people are workers.
就算不想栽赃 你也要知道怎么做
Don't wanna plant it, but you know how it is.
所以他们不介意
So they don't mind it.
告诉我 你打听他干什么?
So tell me something, what you fucking with him for?
他骗了我
He lied to me.
我想不出他有什么理由要骗我
I can't think of one reason big enough for him to lie
因为他骗我的是无关紧要的小事
that's small enough not to matter.
好 瞧
All right, look.
我知道一件事 但也是听说的 你可以听一下
I know one thing, but it's third party, so you gotta play it like that.
海琳和雷在6月吞了奶酪的钱 对吗?
Helene and Ray took Cheese's money back in June, right?
对
Yeah.
一周后 瑞米来到DCU问一个警员
One week later, Remy goes to a cop in DCU
有没有人知道是谁吞了奶酪的钱
asking if anybody knew who robbed Cheese.
然后呢?
So what?
我的眼线告诉我
So my informant tells me,
奶酪过了两周才知道他的钱被吞了
Cheese didn't even know he got robbed until two weeks later.
那么瑞米比奶酪先知道 他的钱被吞了?
So Remy knew Cheese got robbed before Cheese did?
他怎么知道的?
How'd he know that?
我来告诉你
Let me tell you something.
在你开始东奔西走调查警察之前
You better think long and hard
你最好认真地想一想
before you start running around here investigating the police.
你从他们口中夺食 他们会要你的命
You try and take food out their mouths, and they will fuck you up.
谢谢你的牛排
Thanks for the steak.
不用谢
All right.
嘿
Hey.
我明白了
I got it.
我有话和你说 莱昂内尔
We need to talk to you, Lionel.
关于什么?
About what?
关于你房间的隔音效果
About the acoustics in your apartment.
什么?
What?
哦 我们也住在三层公寓 莱昂内尔
Oh, we live in a three-decker, too, Lionel.
我没什么可说的
I got nothing to talk about.
好 不错 我们可以和州警说
Well, that's fine. We can talk to the state police.
在默菲酒吧见我
Meet me at Murphy's Law.
不要去默菲酒吧见他
I don't meet him down Murphy's,
他会报警的
he's gonna call the staties.
他在算计你 不要去那里
He's putting a move on you. Don't go down there.
我能应付帕特里克·肯奇
I can handle Patrick Kenzie.
- 这是我们发的誓 - 是我带头的
- This is an oath we took. - I started this.
- 我要保护它 - 我也有要保护的东西
- This has to be protected. - I got things to protect, too.
- 听我说! - 好的 瑞米
- Listen to me! - All right, Remy.
你要是离开那间屋子 就是我的敌人
You leave that house, you're an enemy to me.
- 相信我 好吗? - 不!相信我
- Just trust me, all right? - No! Trust me!
在我家乡 人们把秘密带到棺材里!
Where I come from, you die with your secrets!
你认识瑞米多久了?
How long have you known Remy?
布里桑特侦探?就在…
Detective Bressant? Just in...
阿曼达的调查中认识他的
Met him through the investigation of Amanda.
- 就这样? - 是的
- That's it? - Yeah.
你认识瑞米多久了?
How long you known Remy?
这是干什么?
What is this?
现在有互联网了 莱昂内尔
They got the Internet, now, Lionel.
你知道镇上的每个人相互都认识
You know how it is in town. Everybody knows everybody.
不 不是每个人都相互认识
No. Everybody don't know everybody.
- 你想说什么? - 你为什么撒谎?
- What're you talking about? - Why you lying?
我没有
I'm not.
你在我们见面的第一天就撒了个弥天大谎
You bragged about taking a hard bust on the first day we met you.
- 不 我没有 - 放屁
- No, I didn't. - Bullshit.
你隐瞒了一些事情 莱昂内尔 你最好说出来
You're hiding something, Lionel, and you better fucking tell it,
因为是你来到我们家 要我们帮你
'cause you came to our house and you asked us for help.
我们千辛万苦去救阿曼达
And we killed ourselves trying to save Amanda.
我现在知道你有事瞒着我
And I know you ain't being 100% with me right now,
你撒的谎让我真的很生气
and it's really fucking pissing me off that you're lying,
所以你最好快点打断我 我就要失去…
so you better interrupt me at any time, 'cause I'm about to lose...
好的 好 好 不要心脏病发作
Okay. Fine, fine. All right? Don't have a heart attack.
我没有跟你说实话
I haven't been honest with you.
那不是什么值得骄傲的事情
It's just not something I'm proud of. You know?
有一天我在酒吧斗殴
I got in a bar fight back in the day.
对方的头骨被打破了
The other guy cracked his skull.
在对打的时候 我肯定说过 "我要杀了你"
At some point, I must've said, "I'll kill you."
我因为故意伤害被捕 我交待的情节和对方不一样
So they had me up for attempted. It's my word against this other guy's.
目击者证实了我说的话 陪审团相信了他
Witness testified to my version and the jury believed him.
- 因为他是个警察 - 是的 他为我作证
- 'Cause he was a cop. - Yeah, he testified for me.
你就是这样认识了布里桑特侦探
So you knew Detective Bressant.
- 我们不是特别要好的朋友 - 但你撒了谎
- It's not like we were best friends. - But you lied.
- 你为什么叫瑞米帮忙? - 他是个警察
- Why did you call Remy? - He's a cop.
- 那不是你叫他帮忙的原因 莱昂内尔 - 得了
- That's not why you called him, Lionel. - Come on.
你家地方很小 他们吵架你都听得见
It's a small place. You heard them arguing.
- 他们吵得很响 - 谁?谁…谁…
- They were being loud. - Who? Who... Who...
所以你叫了瑞米 你和他绑架阿曼达来勒索你妹妹
So you called Remy, and you and him took Amanda to blackmail your sister.
我为什么要这么做?
Why would I do that?
我不知道 莱昂内尔 我真不知道
I don't know, Lionel. I really don't know.
也许是因为 虽然你"浪子回头"这么多年
Maybe because after all the "I put the fucking plug in the jug,"
虽然你又是"细数主恩" 又是"嘴上积德"
and the "count your blessings" and the "watch your language,"
其实你还是和其他人一样
you're just like everybody else.
看到一袋钱就想得到它
You saw a bag of money and you wanted it.
你认为可以逃过法网
And you thought you could get away with it.
但是碧通知了媒体 把事情搞大了
But Bea called the media and made a big thing of it.
接着她找了我们 你就傻眼了
And then she called us, and then you were fucked.
这个案子结了 帕特里克 这个案子结了
The case is closed, Patrick. The case is closed.
贩毒的海地人是栽赃的好对象
Coke-dealing Haitian's a pretty easy target for a frame.
- 莱昂内尔? - 劳驾
- Lionel? - Excuse me.
- 看着我 - 好的 劳驾
- Look at me. - Okay. Excuse me.
你抓了你的外甥女 然后嫁祸给一个黑人
You took your niece, and you laid it off on a black guy.
- 劳驾 - 莱昂内尔 告诉我发生了什么
- Pardon me. - Lionel, tell me what happened.
服务员能来一下吗?
Can I get some service?
好的
Yeah.
干什么?
What?
- 三杯顺风威士忌 一瓶tallboy - 好的
- Three shots of Cutty and a tallboy. - Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
让我想一下
Just give me a second.
二十三年不算短 对吗?
Twenty-three years is something, right?
继续
Go.
我过来照看阿曼达 她和往常一样孤单
I come up to check on Amanda. She was alone as usual.
海琳和雷回家时 我正给她讲故事
I was reading her a story when Helene and Ray come home.
他们不知道我在那里
They didn't know I was there.
别鬼叫了 我女儿在那里睡觉
Stop fucking yelling, my daughter's sleeping in there.
他们开始讲要怎样私吞那个毒贩的钱
They started talking about how they'd robbed this drug dealer.
你知道如果他发现了会做什么吗?
You know what he's fucking gonna do if he finds out?
钱怎么办?
What's the monkey gonna do?
- 哦 你知道… - 我不…
- Oh, you know... - I'm not...
他们说要离开这个州
And they were talking about leaving the state.
所以我打电话给瑞米 告诉了他
So I called Remy and told him.
另外一个毒贩到了纳舒厄 带着可卡因…
There's another drug run up to Nashua. Taking cocaine...
然后呢?
And then what?
我们带走了她
We took her.
瑞米定了这个计划 看上去很简单
Remy laid out this plan. It seemed easy.
我们带走她 逼海琳和雷把钱吐出来
We take her, force Helene and Ray to cough up the cash,
然后放她回去
then we put her back. You know?
阿曼达在乡下度过一个周末
Amanda gets to spend a weekend in the country.
我妹妹尝到一个教训
My sister learns a lesson.
该死的 这样一来人人都有收获
And fuck it, everybody gets paid on top of it.
拿奶酪这种人的钱我问心无愧
I got no problem taking money from a guy like Cheese.
警察那边有他们应付
They were gonna handle the cops.
但是 碧 她急疯了
But Bea, she went nuts.
开始通知报纸 雇用你
Started calling the papers. Hired you.
莱昂内尔不希望我来这 现在你们还不想接这份工作?
Lionel don't want me coming here, now you don't want the job?
但是你找到了钱 结果阿曼达和钱都在他们手里了
But once you found the money, they had Amanda and the money.
所以他们决定做一笔假交易给你看
So they decided to set up a fake exchange for you to witness.
他们买通克里斯·穆伦 在采石场陷害奶酪
They got Chris Mullen to set up Cheese at the quarry.
1万5千美金和一个当老大的机会
15K and a chance to be the boss.
奶酪明白了是怎么回事
Cheese figured out what was happening.
虽然为时已晚 他还是开了枪
Even though it was too late, he started shooting.
慌乱中
Panicking.
她就掉下去了 我是说 她就…
And she just fell. I mean, she just...
掉了下去
She fell in.
她没了
She's gone.
那是一个意外 只是一个意外
It was an accident. It was just an accident.
她是你妹妹的孩子
She was your sister's kid, Lionel.
- 你妹妹的孩子 - 你以为我不想她?
- Your sister's child. - You think I don't miss her?
比起海琳 她更像我的孩子
She was more my kid than Helene's.
去年夏天 海琳和道蒂 带阿曼达去了海滩
Last summer, Helene and Dottie took Amanda to the beach.
那天真的很热 阿曼达睡着了
It was a real hot day. Amanda fell asleep.
她们把她留在车里 自己奔向沙滩
They left her in the car while they go off into the dunes,
和别人一起抽大麻
smoke a doobie with some guys.
两个小时
Two hours.
阿曼达差点被烤熟了
Amanda literally roasted.
她才三岁
She was three.
后来 我抱着她 试图帮她入睡
Later on, I was holding her, trying to help her get to sleep.
我的小阿曼达 她太热了
My little Amanda, she was so hot.
就像刚从炉子里出来的
She felt like something just come out of the oven.
就像罐焖肉一样
Like a fucking pot roast.
所以不要替我妹妹难过
So don't feel too sorry for my sister.
因为她除了自己从没关心过任何人
Because she never gave a shit about anyone but herself.
伙计 打开保险柜 快
Bartender. Open the safe. Now.
每个人都闭嘴 别吵 趴在地上 趴在地上!
Everybody needs to shut up and stay calm. On the floor. On the floor!
- 手抱头 快 - 哦 天哪
- Hands on your head. Do it. - Oh, my God.
每个人都要静下来 一分钟里完成
Everybody stays calm, this'll be over in a minute.
嘿 你知道这个酒吧是谁的吗 混蛋?
Hey, do you know whose bar this is, shithead?
你可以放聪明点 全看你的了
Or you can get wise, it's up to you.
你们说了什么?
What did you say?
你很喜欢嚼舌头 嗯?
You're a talker, huh?
再说啊 他妈的
Just keep revving, motherfucker.
照他说的做 他有枪
Don't antagonize him. He's got a gun.
- 哦 继续说呵 - 我一个字也没说
- Oh, just keep yapping away. - I didn't say nothing.
你应该学会闭嘴
You should learn to keep your mouth shut.
看在上帝的份上闭嘴吧
Shut the fuck up, for Christ's sake.
- 再说啊 伙计 - 我一个字都没说
- Just keep talking, pal. - I didn't say nothing.
闭眼
Close your eyes.
- 该死的 - 瑞米·布里桑特
- Fuck! - Remy Bressant.
是瑞米·布里桑特绑架了 阿曼达·麦克雷蒂
Amanda McCready was taken by Remy Bressant.
哦 该死的 天哪 是瑞米·布里桑特 绑架了阿曼达·麦克雷蒂
Oh, fuck, God. Amanda McCready was taken by Remy Bressant!
- 等等 上帝 - 瑞米·布里桑特
- Wait. Wait. Jesus. - Remy Bressant.
去他的 瑞米·布里桑特!
God damn it. Remy Bressant!
阿曼达·麦克雷蒂被绑架了
Amanda McCready was taken
- 瑞米·布里桑特干的 - 上帝啊 我告诉他了
- by Remy Bressant. - Jesus. I told him.
我告诉他我们为了勒索钱财绑架她 我告诉了他 我告诉了他 瑞米
I told him we took her for ransom. I told him. I told him, Remy.
求你了 我告诉他为了勒索钱财绑架她 我已经说了
Please, I told him we took her for ransom. I did it.
瑞米 求你了
Remy, please.
求你了
Please.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
和他呆在一块
Stay with him.
放下你的枪
Drop your gun.
放下!
Put it down!
那伙计来真的
That bartender wasn't fucking around.
你做了什么?
What did you do?
是你害死了她?
Did you get her killed?
说是
Say yes.
说是!
Say yes!
你打算做什么?打死我? 是 是 是
What're you gonna do? Shoot me? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
她是个孩子
She was a child.
我喜欢孩子
I love children.
为什么我要揭露我自己参与的阴谋?
Why would I expose a conspiracy that I was a part of?
我是说 莱昂内尔和我说的有矛盾吗?
I mean, did Lionel contradict anything I've said?
酒吧里其他目击者跟我说的有矛盾吗?
Did any of the witnesses at the bar contradict anything I've said?
一个警官今天被杀了 这可不是小事
A police officer was killed today. That's not looked on lightly.
贪污腐败难道是小事?
Is corruption looked on lightly?
小女孩被害死难道是小事?
Is a little girl getting killed looked on lightly?
噢 冷静
Whoa, hold on.
你是收费的私人侦探
You charge people money as a detective.
那天晚上你在采石场 对吗?
Now, you're at the quarry the other night, right?
你不知道那是一个骗局?
And you have no idea that this is a setup?
你被蒙在鼓里 对吗?
You're baffled. Right?
不 也许你觉得很奇怪 其实我上当是因为
No, because, strange as it might seem,
警察告诉我的事情我总是相信的
I believe the police when they tell me something.
你是个菜鸟 你知道么?
You're a fresh prick. You know that?
因为我看到一张勒索的纸条 和阿曼达·麦克雷蒂的毯子
And because I had a ransom note and Amanda McCready's blanket
就放在我的邮箱里
put in my mailbox.
因为我看到一份电话记录 是奶酪打到警察局的
And because I read a transcript of a call that Cheese put into the station.
一个911报警电话?
A 911 call?
不 是奶酪打到警局的电话
No, it was a call Cheese made to the station.
打给在警局的瑞米·布里桑特
To Remy Bressant at the station.
或者是克里斯·穆伦冒充奶酪打的
Or that Chris Mullen made, pretending to be Cheese.
不管是什么 反正录下来了
Or whatever the fuck it was, but it was recorded,
一个电话
and there was a call.
我们不会给打到警局的电话录音
We don't record calls coming into the station,
我们也不做文字记录 聪明人
and we don't do transcripts, smart guy.
那么 你听到磁带了?
So, did you hear a tape?
- 不 我没有听到 - 好的
- No, I didn't hear a tape. - Okay.
你看到文字记录了?
Did you see a transcript?
不 我肯定记错了
No, I must've remembered it wrong.
孩子们只会宽恕
Kids forgive.
他们这样做 得到的是什么?
What do they get for it?
阿曼达差点被烤熟了
Amanda literally roasted.
你以为我不想她?
You think I don't miss her.
比起海琳 她更像我的孩子
She was more my kid than Helene's.
我喜欢孩子
I love children.
如果这是你想做的事情 帕特里克 你要确定
This is the kind of thing that if you do, Patrick, you wanna be sure.
你确定吗?
Are you sure?
不
No.
你来吗?
Are you coming?
不
No.
72年 是道伊尔把 瑞米从路易斯安那带过来的
Doyle brought Remy from Louisiana back in '72.
读读重点标出的那段好吗?
Care to read the highlighted portion?
要去旅游?
Taking a trip?
帕特里克·肯奇
Patrick Kenzie.
我为什么不能去开心一下?
To what do I owe the pleasure?
瑞米·布里桑特昨晚死了
Remy Bressant died last night.
我听说了 那很不光彩
I was told. It's a shame.
是的 很难理解 因为他看上去像个好人
Yeah, it's hard to understand. Because he seemed like a good man.
他是个好人
He was a good man.
我们不知道人们为何行事
We don't know why people do what they do.
每个人都从自己的那扇窗看出去
Everybody looks out his own window.
每个人都有自己的理由
And everyone's got their reasons.
- 嘿 - 嗨
- Hey. - Hi.
- 你好吗? - 很好
- How are you? - Good.
- 尼克 他们正在向我开火
Nick! They're firing at me.
尼克 你听得见我说话吗?你还好吗? 他们正在向我开火
Nick, you hear me? You okay? They're firing at me!
瑞米!
Remy!
- 我听见有东西掉进水里了! - 有埋伏!有埋伏!
- I heard something go in the water! - Ambush! Ambush!
- 有东西掉进去了! - 跑 瑞米 跑!
- Something went in! - Run. Remy. Run!
慌乱中
Panicking.
阿曼达吓坏了 她开始跑
Amanda got scared. She started running.
她就掉下去了 我是说 她就掉下去了
She just fell. I mean, she just fell in.
克里斯·穆伦 29岁
Twenty-nine-year-old Chris Mullen
昨晚被枪杀
was gunned down last night
原因显然是遭遇抢劫
in an apparent robbery.
你进去陪陪弗兰 爸爸马上就进来
You go back inside with Frannie. Papa will come in soon.
给你做三明治 好吗?
Make you a sandwich, okay?
- 好的 - 真是乖孩子
- All right. - That's my girl.
不要去那里
Don't go down there.
如果我觉得他有证据 我来承担责任
If I think he has the evidence, I'll take the hit.
我没有问题
I got no problem doing the time.
闭嘴 那是阿曼达和她的人生
Fuck up, and it's Amanda and her life.
- 好的 - 我也有要保护的东西
- All right. - I got things to protect, too.
你要是离开那间屋子 就是我的敌人
You leave that house, you're an enemy to me
你会伤害到阿曼达的
and you're a danger to Amanda.
求你了 我告诉他为了勒索钱财绑架她 我已经说了
Please, I told him we took her for ransom. I did it.
我告诉他了 瑞米 求你了
I told him. Remy, please.
现在你知道了
So now you know.
我妹妹生活不稳定 她嗑药
My sister's not stable. She's on crack.
她说要离开这个州 我担心我的外甥女
She's talking about leaving the state. I'm scared for my niece.
- 谁来照顾她? - 我们要采取行动
- Who's gonna take care of her? - We'll do something.
我们要想办法 她是瘾君子
We'll figure it out. She's an addict.
本性难移 无可救药
Bigot. Drug mule.
这个孩子会死 或者不出10年就成为街上的太妹
The child will be dead or on the street in 10 years.
- 她舅舅怎么办? - 他不会告诉任何人
- What about the uncle? - He can never tell anyone.
连他妻子都不告诉 否则他就再也见不到她
Not even his wife. Or he'll never see her again.
对他来说这值得 他知道她会过得更好
It's worth it to him. Know she'll have a better life.
在我们退休前 再做一件好事
Do one last good thing before we hang it up.
我们眼看着多少孩子被毁了?
How many children have we seen destroyed?
够多了
Enough.
这样让你感觉好些吗?
Does it make you feel better?
告诉你自己你做这件事 是出于正当的理由
Telling yourself you did it for the right reasons?
你为了救她
That you took her to be saved.
从母亲手里夺走她?
From her own mother?
我们只是要给 一个小女孩正常的人生
We're just trying to give a little girl a life.
你不能给她人生 海琳才是她妈妈
Wasn't your life to give. Helene's her mother.
如果你觉得她不是合格的母亲 你应该找社会服务机构
If you thought she was a bad mother, you should've gone to Social Services.
不管怎样 她是她妈妈 那才是她的归宿
Short of that, she's her mother, and that's where she belongs.
你转身
You turn around.
回到你的车上 等上30年
You go back to your fucking car, and you wait 30 years.
你还不知道世界是怎么回事
You don't know what the world is made of yet.
5分钟后我会报警 他们10分钟后到
I'm calling state police in five minutes. They'll be here in ten.
你本应该现在就做
Thought you would've done that by now.
你知道你为什么不那么做?
You know why you haven't?
因为你想到这可能是个不可挽回的错误
Because you think this might be an irreparable mistake.
因为在你心灵深处 你知道法规怎么说都不重要
Because deep inside you, you know it doesn't matter what the rules say.
当你熄灭灯光扪心自问
When the lights go out and you ask yourself,
"她在那更好还是在这更好?" 你知道答案
"Is she better off here or better off there," you know the answer.
你会经常这样
And you always will.
你…你有机会做正确的事
You... You could do a right thing here.
一件善事
A good thing.
有人活一辈子都没有这样的机会
Men live their whole lives without getting this chance.
如果你放弃机会
You walk away from it,
可能你回家的时候 不会觉得后悔
you may not regret it when you get home.
也可能一整年都不后悔
You may not regret it for a year,
但是当你处在我的位置 我保证 你会后悔
but when you get to where I am, I promise you, you will.
我会离世 你会老去 但她…
I'll be dead, you'll be old. But she...
她自己会拖着一群衣衫褴褛 脏乱不堪的孩子
She'll be dragging around a couple of tattered, damaged children of her own,
你会是那个不得不跟她说对不起的人
and you'll be the one who has to tell them you're sorry.
你知道吗?那些事可能会发生
You know what? Maybe that'll happen.
如果发生了 我会道歉 我会承受一切
And if it does, I'll tell them I'm sorry, and I'll live with it.
但是有件事永远不会发生 我也不想做
But what's never gonna happen and what I'm not gonna do
那就是对一个长大了的女士道歉
is have to apologize to a grown woman
她过来对我说
who comes to me and says,
我小时候被绑架了
"I was kidnapped when I was a little girl,
我舅妈雇了你来找我
"and my aunt hired you to find me.
你找到了 你发现我在一个陌生的家庭
"And you did, you found me with some strange family.
但是你违背了诺言 把我丢在那里
"But you broke your promise and you left me there.
为什么?为什么你不带我回家?
"Why? Why didn't you bring me home?
所有的零食 服装和旅游都不重要
"Because all the snacks and the outfits and the family trips don't matter.
他们偷偷带走了我
"They stole me.
那不是我的家庭 你知道的
"It wasn't my family and you knew about it
你全都知道 但是无所作为
"and you knew better and you did nothing."
也许那个长大了的女士会原谅我
And maybe that grown woman will forgive me,
但是我永远不会原谅我自己
but I'll never forgive myself.
我做我该做的事 为了孩子
I did what I did for the sake of the child.
好吧 也为了我
All right. For me, too.
但是现在 我求你看在孩子的份上
But now, I'm asking you for the sake of the child.
我恳求你
I'm begging you.
你考虑一下
You think about it.
她很开心
She's happy.
什么?
What?
她在这里很开心 我看到她了
She's happy here. I saw her.
安姬 不要这样
Angie, don't do this.
如果你报警 她会被送回去
If you call the police, they will send her back.
我不是要把她送到别的地方去 海琳是她母亲
I'm not sending her anywhere. Helene is her mother.
她在这更好
She's better off here.
为什么?因为他有钱 可以为她做三明治?
Why? Because he's got money, and he makes her sandwiches?
因为他爱她
Because he loves her.
- 海琳也爱她 - 海琳不会那样善待她
- Helene loves her, too. - Helene doesn't treat her that way.
好 也许她会变
Well, maybe she'll change.
她不会变 人们本性难移
She won't change. People don't change.
海琳并非善类
Helene is arsenic.
安姬 我知道这很难
Angie, I know that this is hard.
看着我 我知道很难
Look at me, I know it's hard.
但是我需要你站在我这边 我要你说:
But I need you to stand by me. I need you to say,
我们做了正确的决定
"We're gonna make the right decision,
我们会让事情好转
"and we're gonna make everything okay."
一切都会好的
Everything will be okay.
因为我们要把她留在这
Because we're gonna leave her here,
我们会不时谈起她
and every now and then we're gonna talk about her.
她在哪里 她读几年级
And where she is, and about what grade she's in.
一切都会好 因为我们知道 她在什么学校里
And that'll be okay, because we're gonna know what school she's in,
我们会知道她很快乐 她有生日聚会
and we're gonna know she's happy, and she's got birthday parties,
每天她都欢笑 一觉睡到天亮
and she smiles every day, and she has sleepovers.
亲爱的 对不起
Baby, I'm sorry.
但你不能要我做一些我做不到的事情
But you can't ask me to do something that I can't do.
那么你也不能要我忍受这样的事
And you can't ask me to live with it.
帕特里克 为了我 求你了?
Patrick, for me. Please?
我会因此恨你 而我不想这样
I will hate you for doing this, and I don't want to.
曾经是正义的象征 勇士的楷模
Once an icon of justice and a model for crusaders,
杰克·道伊尔今晚锒铛入狱 埃芙琳?
Jack Doyle is behind bars tonight. Evelyn?
根据法律要求 社会服务机构
Social Services, as demanded by law,
会先花些时间对阿曼达体检 然后再带她回家
will take time to examine little Amanda before returning her to home,
回到母亲的怀抱
and the arms of a mother who never gave up hope
这位母亲从未放弃再次看到女儿的希望
that she would see her daughter again.
- 海琳 你觉得怎么样… - 海琳 感觉如何
- Helene, how do you feel... - Helene, what does it feel like
- 现在你和女儿团聚了? - 觉得怎么样?
- to have your daughter with you now? - How do you feel?
海琳 你现在觉得好吗?感觉怎么样…
Helene, how you feeling right now? How you feeling...
后退 后退 后退
Back up. Back up. Back up. Back up.
阿曼达 看到妈妈感觉怎么样?
Amanda, how do you feel to see your mom?
嘿 阿曼达
Hey, Amanda.
海琳 你觉得怎样?
Helene, how you feeling?
- 告诉我们你的感觉 - 告诉我们你现在在想什么
- Tell us how it feels. - Tell us what you're thinking right now.
你一定很激动 告诉我们你的感受
You must be so excited. Give us your feelings.
我 我的宝贝 噢 宝贝
Oh, my sweetheart. Oh, my.
海琳 全世界都想知道你现在的感受
Helene, the whole world wants to know what you're feeling right now.
你好吗 宝贝?
How are you, sweetheart?
我心里百感交集
Oh, my heart is brimming.
上帝保佑所有人 谢谢所有人
And just God bless to everyone and thank you to all...
所有的警察和消防员
To all the policemen and the firemen,
我现在喜欢911
I feel like 9l11 right now.
哦 我向上帝发誓 我是说 就…
Oh, I swear to God, I mean, just...
你要对那些和你情况相似的父母
Do you have any comments for parents out there
说些什么吗?
that might be in a similar situation?
哦 不要让孩子脱离你的视线
Oh, just never let your kids out of your sight.
别把他们交给任何人
Don't trust them to no one.
把他们抱在自己怀里
And just keep them in your arms,
只要你心里惦记着他们 就该把他们抱在自己怀里
as much as they're in your heart, you keep them in your arms.
怎么样?一个大团圆的结局
How about that? A great end to that story.
- 对所有人都是个好消息 - 是的
- Good news for everybody. - Yes, it is.
瑞米·布里桑特 1948-2007
- 对不起 我来拿些东西 - 好吧
- Sorry, I had to get some stuff. - It's all right.
你想谈一下吗?
You wanna talk for a minute?
无话可说
There's nothing to say.
团圆! 阿曼达回家
对不起 我大概过两分钟就要走
Sorry for being rude, I gotta be out of here in, like, two minutes.
做你的事情吧
Do your thing.
- 你觉得他会喜欢我吗? - 谁?
- Think he'll like me? - Who?
我的约会对象
My date.
哦 怎么不会?
Oh, how could he not?
你嘴真甜
You're sweet.
他在"美国受害人"节目里看到我
He seen me on my American Victim.
他给我写了几封信 我回答"随你便"
He wrote me letters, I was like, "Whatever."
但是后来他又在梅瑞迪丝·薇拉的节目 里看到我 就从普罗维登斯开车过来
But then he seen my Meredith Vieira, he drove down here from Providence.
我觉得 这很浪漫 对吗?
I'm like, "That's romantic." Right?
你的女友怎么样了?
How's your girlfriend?
她很好 她去北岸和姐姐一起住了
She's all right, she's at the North Shore with her sister.
哦 希望她能有个比我好的家庭 对吗?
Oh, hope she got better family than I do, right?
那些下流的王八蛋
Those dirty motherfuckers.
要是她不学聪明点 我就干掉你
She don't get smart, I'll take you out.
- 碧怎么样? - 该死的碧
- How's Bea? - Fuck Bea.
我不准她来这公寓
I banned her from the apartment.
她卖了她的单元 住到高档的梅尔罗斯去了
She sold her unit, moved out fancy-pants Melrose.
不要以为她不恨你 你让莱昂内尔进了监狱
Don't think she don't hate you for Lionel going to jail, neither.
哦 也许就是因为这个 她没有付我钱
Well, that's probably why she never paid my bill.
你应该起诉他
You should fucking sue.
你呢 海琳?
How about you, Helene?
你恨我吗?
You hate me?
当然不
Fuck no.
是我哥哥又怎样?他带走了我的孩子 该死的莱昂内尔 她可能受伤的
Brother or not, he took my kid. Fuck Lionel. She could have been hurt.
- 阿曼达怎么样? - 什么阿曼达怎么样?
- What about Amanda? - What about Amanda?
- 谁来照看她? - 道蒂
- Who's gonna watch her? - Dottie.
好 道蒂知道了吗?
Yeah, does Dottie know that?
- 她五分钟后到 - 很好
- She will in five minutes. - Great.
该死 我也要迟到了 你不介意的话照看她一下
Fuck, I'm gonna be late, too. Unless you don't mind sitting for her.
- 好 当然可以 - 当真?
- Yeah, sure. - For real?
- 对 很乐意 - 她喜欢你
- Yeah, that's fine. - She likes you.
再见 甜心
Bye, sweetheart.
你是个大好人 帕特里克
You're a godsend, Patrick.
再见
Bye.
这是米拉贝尔吗?
Is that Mirabelle?
是安娜贝尔
Annabelle.
TLF中文字幕站
http://tlfsubs.eastgame.net